<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="RdCv2n1-en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Revue des Colonies V.2 N°1 (selection in English translation)</title>
            <editor>Maria Beliaeva Solomon</editor>
         </titleStmt>
         <xi:include href="shared/editionStmt.xml"/>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
      <pb n="1" facs="v2n1p1"/>
         <titlePage>
            <titlePart type="main"><seg>REVUE</seg><lb/>DES<lb/><seg>COLONIES</seg></titlePart>
            <titlePart type="sub">MONTHLY COMPENDIUM<lb/> OF POLITICS, ADMINISTRATION, JUSTICE,
               INSTRUCTION AND COLONIAL CUSTOMS,</titlePart>
            <byline>DIRECTED<lb/> <hi rend="bold">BY</hi> <persName ref="#CB">C.-A. BISSETTE</persName>.</byline>
            <docEdition>2nd year — n.1 — July.<lb/></docEdition>
            <figure>
               <graphic url="v2n1-vignette.jpg"/>
               <figDesc>Am I not a man and your brother?....<ptr target="#n6D92"/></figDesc>
            </figure>
            <docImprint><pubPlace><settlement>PARIS</settlement>,<lb/> AT THE OFFICE OF THE REVUE DES COLONIES, <lb/> 28, RUE LOUIS-LE-GRAND.</pubPlace><lb/> <date>1835</date>.</docImprint>
         </titlePage>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div>
         <pb n="3" facs="v2n1p3"/>
            <head n="Revue Des Colonies">REVUE DES COLONIES</head>
            <head n="2nd Year. July 1835. N° 1.">2nd YEAR. JULY 1835. N° 1.</head>
            <div>
               <list>
                  <item>On the abolition of slavery by the National Convention.</item> 
                  <item>— Bill for the abolition of slavery.</item>
                  <item>— Inquiry into the colonies, Vote on the last law on the colonies.</item>
                  <item>— Electoral question.</item>
                  <item>— FRANCE. House of Representatives. Discussion of the budget of the Navy
                  and the Colonies.</item> 
                  <item>— Of the passing of the law relating to criminal legislation.</item>
                  <item>— Chamber of Peers.</item>
                  <item>— Discussion of the law of an additional credit of 650,000
                  francs granted to the Minister of the Navy and the Colonies.</item> 
                  <item>— Foreign colonies. Bermuda. Barbados.</item>
                  <item>— Miscellaneous News.</item>
                  <item>— Varieties.</item>
                  <item>— Biography.</item>
                  <item>— Poetry.</item>
                  <item>— Bibliography.<ptr target="#n9D67"/></item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="abolition">
               <head n="On the Abolition of Slavery by the National Convention. — Revue Des Colonies Bill.">ON THE ABOLITION OF SLAVERY BY THE NATIONAL CONVENTION. — REVUE DES COLONIES
                  BILL.</head>
               <p> Slavery, which is tending to disappear completely and in all its forms from human
                  societies, and the abolition of which by legislative means in our colonies cannot
                  be long in coming, was once already outlawed, with admirable spontaneity, by the
                     <orgName ref="#CNat">National Convention</orgName>. The National Convention did
                  not put off this just reparation for an hour, and from the moment that the
                  question had been submitted, it was resolved without hesitation in the direction
                  of the revolution and of the philosophical spirit of the eighteenth century;
                  better said yet, it was not even a question. In the first preoccupations of '89,
                  the colonies were only considered momentarily. In a rush, free men of color were
                  called to enjoy the rights of citizenship. In the colonies themselves, the
                  question, although then as now at the heart of the matter, was kept as far as
                  possible out of discussion by a kind of apprehension and vague dread of the
                  future.</p>
               <p> However, the French Revolution had taken effect. The new ideas distributed by the
                  press, spread by the word, had crossed the seas<ptr target="#n5676"/>; the French Antilles<ptr target="#n2B16"/> were also consumed with this new state of mind.
                  In general, however, it was only among the whites that parties had been formed. In
                  the colonies<pb n="4" facs="v2n1p4"/> as in France there were revolutionaries, and
                  counter-revolutionaries, supporters of royalty and supporters of democracy. The
                  tricolor flag had appeared to some as an odious sign, to others, a glorious sign;
                  the latter were the most numerous, the former the richest. Hence divisions,
                  parties; a silent disagreement between those who clung desperately to the
                  privileges of the past, and those whom the breath of new liberty had touched as it
                  crossed the seas. The debate was still only between them. Of the liberation of
                  slaves, not a clear and distinct word, as if the rights of man had not been
                  proclaimed and the Bastille had not been taken. By whatever names the colonists
                  used, republican or royalist, none among them was led by the spirit of age<ptr target="#n17AB"/> to draw from the principles that they claimed for themselves,
                  a conclusion favorable to the freedom of the other race; the distinction of color
                  remained, slavery was the holy ark which no one dreamed of touching.</p>
               <p>However, the counter-revolutionary work advanced, <placeName ref="#ANG">England</placeName>, then at the head of the retrograde movement, attacked us
                  everywhere in the two seas. Mistress of <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, poorly defended by its inhabitants, of whom several,
                  and of the highest rank, were traitors to the fatherland (1),<ptr target="#n239B"/> England had vainly tried to conquer several other points, including <placeName ref="#GP">Guadeloupe</placeName> and <placeName ref="#HT">Saint-Domingue</placeName>. Saint-Domingue, however, was seriously threatened.
                  At the first news of the danger, the National Convention sent two of its members
                  to organize the defense: they found nothing but dispiritedness.</p>
               <p>In the most perilous circumstances, the commissioners had recourse to a great
                  measure of public safety, completely conforming to the</p>
               <p>
                  <note>(1) M. le Chevalier Dubuc, who then was at the head of the colonial
                     committee in Martinique, crossed furtively to the island of Dominica, whence he
                     embarked for England, and returned with the English Admiral Gardener to attempt
                     the conquest of Martinique. This expedition, which was repelled with heavy
                     losses, did not discourage M. Dubuc; he returned to England, and succeeded in
                     inducing the British government to grant him, as well as M. de Clairfontaine,
                     deputy for Guadeloupe, new forces for the conquest of Guadeloupe and
                     Martinique. A squadron, under the orders of Admiral Jervis, and an army under
                     the orders of General Grey, seized Martinique in 1794. Guadeloupe thus fell
                     into the power of the English, but they were driven out forty days
                     later.</note></p>
               <pb n="5" facs="v2n1p5"/>
               <p>nature of their mission and for which they took full responsibility: they called
                  the slaves to freedom. The slaves rushed in mass to the defense of the colony, and
                  from then on the blacks<ptr target="#n4F06"/> were won over to the great cause of
                  the French republic.</p>
               <p> In the meantime, an election was held in Saint-Domingue in which all classes of
                  the population took part, without distinction of color. <persName ref="#Dfy">Dufahy</persName> a man of courage and heart, who had shown in the
                  administration of his properties at Saint-Domingue an unequivocal sympathy for the
                  oppressed race, was one of the deputies appointed on this occasion.</p>
               <p>Scarcely had the National Convention learned of the acts of <persName ref="#Plv">Polverel</persName> and of <persName ref="#Stx">Sonthonax</persName>, its
                  commissioners with regard to everything concerning slaves, that it approved them;
                  their greatness was recognized. And immediately, to the applause of the immortal
                  assembly, was pronounced forthwith, at the request of Dufahy, not only the
                  emancipation of the entire black race, but also its reintegration into the great
                  national family.<ptr target="#nA2CD"/></p>
               <p>Thus was manifested, at the first appeal with regard to the blacks, the French
                  revolution's spirit of justice; and its project of the reintegration of the rights
                  of man, undertaken against all obstacles, seemed for a moment codified
                  forever.</p>
               <p>It was in the month of February 1794, that the National Convention issued the
                  memorable decree which abolished slavery throughout the French
                  colonies; a decree believed to be forever irrevocable.</p>
               <p>All that remained for the French Republic to do was to take pride in this most glorious measure, to which it proceeded with such a resolute spirit and with such firmness. Freedom
                  established itself in consequence, <foreign>de facto</foreign> and <foreign>de jure</foreign>, in
                  those of our colonies which England had not succeeded in seizing.</p>
               <p>The emancipation of the blacks had the first result of preserving for France its
                  richest colony, Saint-Domingue. Once free, the blacks of Saint-Domingue, who it
                  would have been hardly surprising to see comport themselves differently upon
                  achieving liberty, gave striking proofs of their good will, and of their aptitude
                  for all kinds of work. Under this regenerative regime, the colony organized
                  itself, the workshops were all in activity, the crops <pb n="6" facs="v2n1p6"/> flourished. This
                  state of affairs lasted, not without remarkable progress, until 1802, when
                     <persName ref="#NB">Napoleon</persName>, misled by the fatality of his
                  illiberal ideas, tried to reestablish slavery where the National Convention had
                  made it disappear. We must see in Mr. Macaulay's excellent book on Haiti <ptr target="#n8414"/> the curious details of this emancipation, somewhat
                  improvised, of the black race in the most considerable of our colonial possessions
                  of that period. Mr. Macaulay's work is filled not only with unknown facts about
                  the war of independence in <placeName ref="#HT">Haiti</placeName>, but also with irrefutable evidence against the
                  errors propagated with the most flagrant bad faith by the enemies of the cause of
                  the blacks.</p>
               <p> He triumphantly proves that the greatest disasters were the result of the return
                  to slavery in 1802, undertaken beyond all reason and all necessity by the First
                  Consul.</p>
               <p> The French army, fighting for a bad cause, was defeated, and perished. The blacks
                  remained masters of the land, and laid there the foundations of the social state
                  which they enjoy today, a social state far superior to that of many supposedly
                  civilized European nations.<ptr target="#n82F8"/> The problem of free labor in the
                  Antilles was thereby solved, and today the example of the emancipated English
                  colonies must have convinced even the most dimwitted of the falsity and infamy of
                  the assertions of the colonists against the blacks.<ptr target="#n411B"/></p>
               <p> That which was decreed by the National Convention in 1794, for the French
                  possessions, which was established by force of circumstance following the wars of
                  independence of Saint-Domingue, which has just been organized for the English
                  colonies, namely: the emancipation of the blacks and free labor, we claim it today
                  on the most legitimate grounds, in the name of principle and necessity, and we
                  want to establish it by reason and according to a law of justice and reparation,
                  without delay.<ptr target="#n1FC1"/></p>
            </div>
            <pb n="7" facs="v2n1p7"/>
            <div xml:id="bill">
               <head n="Bill for the Abolition of Slavery in the French Colonies.">BILL FOR THE ABOLITION OF SLAVERY IN THE FRENCH COLONIES.</head>
               <p> Considering that slavery is contrary to all divine and human laws; that it could
                  only have been established through violence, injustice and contempt for the most
                  imprescriptible of human rights, the right to dispose of one's person and one's
                  work according to one's will, insofar as this will does not infringe upon the
                  rights of others, which it is for the law alone to determine; considering that
                  slavery is not only a usurpation of man by man, which can no longer be tolerated
                  morally, but furthermore an inexhaustible source of misfortunes, troubles, and
                  concerns of all kinds for the peoples whom it affects; that, moreover, experience
                  has sufficiently proven that wherever slavery persists, only material development
                  can take place, and that it implies contempt for the true principles of social
                  morality;</p>
               <p>By all these causes, etc.</p>
               <p> FIRST ARTICLE.<lb/> Slavery is abolished in all French overseas
                  possessions.<lb/>All the inhabitants of the French colonies, without distinction
                  of color, are declared free and equal in rights.<ptr target="#n0380"/></p>
               <p>ART. 2.<lb/>They therefore enjoy all family, civil and political rights, in the
                  same way as other French citizens, in accordance with the law.</p>
               <p>ART. 3.<lb/>The nature and the quota of the wages between the laborers<ptr target="#n1542"/> and the landowners will be regulated by the government of the
                     metropole.</p>
               <p>ART. 4<lb/> There will be created, in all the communes of the different French
                  colonies, free schools for the civil and religious instruction of the laborers.
                  This instruction will be compulsory for all those who have not reached the age of
                  21.<ptr target="#n3F04"/></p>
               <pb n="8" facs="v2n1p8"/>
               <p>ART. 5.<lb/> A special code called the code of culture will regulate all that
                  concerns the details and the execution of this law.</p>
               <p>ART. 6.<lb/> All laws and ordinances, all regulations whatever, which relate to
                  slavery, are from now on and remain annulled and abrogated.</p>
               <p> This law is but a law of principles; and in this respect it seems to us to
                  establish, in a clear and precise manner, the bases on which the regulatory code
                  of the colonies will need to rest. The six articles that precede are, in a way,
                  only the social charter promulgated in the colonies by the French government. If
                  we do not enter into the examination of the various questions which the
                  establishment of these new principles may raise, our readers will find the reasons
                  for this silence in the article that follows this one, entitled: <title>Inquiry
                     into the colonies</title>.</p>
               <p> We will explain ourselves here on only one point, that of the indemnity that some
                  want to grant and that others refuse to the owners of slaves. We have said nothing
                  about it in the law constituting the social state of the colonies, and here is
                  why:</p>
               <p> Between the master and the slave there can be no question of indemnity.<ptr target="#n3542"/> If one absolutely wanted to establish one, it would be the
                  master who would owe it to the slave, as reparation for the physical and moral
                  violence he has exercised against him.<ptr target="#n678F"/></p>
               <p> The principle of indemnity can only be debated between French society and the
                  colonial landowners. Let us prove that if France granted an indemnity, it would
                  be, on its part, a pure act of liberality, from which, consequently, it would do
                  well to abstain.</p>
               <p>Freedom is neither sold nor acquired. It exists forever, everywhere, and for
                  everyone. One no more loses it under the whip of a master than one buys it for
                  cold cash; and this way of acquiring it strikes more at its principle than the
                  material violence that causes it to be lost, in fact, because this, at least,
                  leaves the right intact. The word indemnity is, accordingly, the one which we have
                  most carefully banished from a bill of principles on the abolition of slavery.<ptr target="#n49AF"/></p>
               <pb n="9" facs="v2n1p9"/>
               <p> This law is therefore not a dispossession, an expropriation, for reasons of
                  public utility; on the contrary, it is the negation of the state of property, to
                  which it puts an end. It is the reestablishment of rights, a real restoration<ptr target="#n09EC"/> this time: in this respect, the indemnity would be immoral.
                  Consider it from a purely material point of view; the colonists would ask France
                  for an indemnity, founded on what? on the actual loss they incur; what is it that
                  they are losing? the purchase price and the fruit of slave labor? Neither; even in
                  the hypothesis most favorable to the slave owners, the purchase price must be put
                  out of the question for the greatest number, since the slave trade has been
                  abolished for a long time, and that it would be unreasonable to found the demand
                  for justice upon the violation of the law. Moreover, the purchase price of a slave
                  is nothing more than a kind of import duty paid in order to be able to take
                  advantage of the labor of the imported <emph>commodity</emph><ptr target="#n07F3"/>. This work is the one and only profit generator of the masters. One should not
                  quantify the particular industry of each slave because under this mode it is
                  exerted too narrowly, too restricted; because intelligence, dulled by servitude,
                  and the ignorance which is its necessary consequence, is without force, without
                  guide, without direction, and because the small savings acquired by the slave are
                  often discarded to him by the master.<ptr target="#n90C0"/> But let us say in passing that this
                  industry, besides the work in the fields, will certainly be one of the means of
                  prosperity of the colonies when it is practiced by free hands and directed by
                  cultivated intelligences.</p>
               <p>The master therefore derives only one profit, either from the slave whom he buys,
                  or from the one who is born on his property: labor; and this profit imposes on him
                  a fairly large number of expenses: food, clothing, care of every kind for the
                  preservation of his slaves.</p>
               <p>Well, the colonies are constituted in such a way that the masters, whatever their
                  rights may be, cannot dispense with having their former slaves work the land, and
                  that these, upon becoming free, will no less be laborers. The law changes, but the
                  fact will not, the master loses nothing; what the labor of his former slaves cost
                  him in overhead will be replaced by the wages he will give to them as free
                  laborers. Let him not come and say that the slave we <pb n="10" facs="v2n1p10"/> removed from
                  under his dominion cost him 1500 and 2000 francs; for he has paid this price and
                  other expenses to profit from a labor that he may always obtain from the will of
                  the worker. Wages replace a great number of cares and expenses, and if, all things
                  considered, there is an increase, that is the fate of all modern industries.</p>
               <p>Who does not see now that by compensating the former owners, the state would use
                  200 million to repair a chimerical evil. We have tried to leave the principles
                  aside for a moment, but if it were true that the dispossession of the master were
                  for him a material loss of money, that would not give him any more right to be
                  compensated; because there is <emph>no right against rights.</emph>.</p>
               <p> One will object, as a delegate in the tribune already has: “The blacks who have
                  become free will no longer work, the landowners will lose, the blacks will gain
                  nothing, the colonies will perish; all this with no advantage to anyone.” Error!
                  societies do not perish; they transform; blacks will work as laborers, and for two
                  reasons: so as not to starve, and in the hopes of obtaining a piece of land. They
                  will work better than before, and their crops, improved in the interest of the
                  landowners, would enable the farmers and workmen to successfully practice the
                  exercise of their industrial imaginations. Observe, moreover, that in all that
                  relates to the colonies, we always ask for an arbiter, France. We conceive nothing
                  without this moderating power; for, indeed, we do not dispute the difficulties
                  which the transition from the old to the new state produced by the abolition of
                  slavery may present; but that is no reason to adjourn the question
                     indefinitely.<ptr target="#n435A"/></p>
               <p>With the help of the French government, the colonies can reform themselves and
                  live without harm to any portion of their inhabitants. Without this intervention,
                  they will certainly not perish as human societies, but they will perish as
                  European societies. There would come a day when an inevitable, terrible struggle
                  would begin, and where force would determine the law. One must not think that, in
                  closing one's eyes, that which offends the gaze disappears, and that facts cease
                  to exist simply because one does not speak of them. The intermediary race of the
                  colonies is the necessary link between the old and the new order, the keystone of
                  the new social edifice.<ptr target="#nA4C7"/> Building on a legal basis, reforming
                  without viol<pb n="11" facs="v2n1p11"/>ence, repairing without damage, such is our aim. It can be
                  accomplished under the patronage of France, and what's more, it can only be
                  accomplished with the aid of France.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <xi:include href="notes/RdCv2n1-notes.xml"/>
         <xi:include href="shared/entities.xml"/>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>