<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xml:id="RdCv1n1-fr">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Revue des Colonies V.5 N°6 (selection in original French)</title>
                <editor>Maria Beliaeva Solomon</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <xi:include href="shared/editionStmt.xml"/>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Information about the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <front></front>
        <body>
            <div>
                <pb n="193" facs="v5n6p13"/>
                <head>REVUE DES COLONIES.</head>
                <div>
                    <head>CORRESPONDENCE</head>
                    <head>LETTER FROM Mr. ALEXANDRE DUMAS.</head>
                    <p>There is a <bibl><title ref="#RC">Revue Coloniale</title></bibl> which differs from the <bibl><title ref="#RdC">Revue des Colonies</title></bibl>, not only in its title, but in its principles and the purpose of its publication. In mentioning this opposition; we do not mean to blame our adversaries. Everyone is perfectly free to write for or against the spirit of reform; but the following letter, which is addressed to us by one of the century’s greatest literary figures, compels us to acknowledge that an opinion contrary to ours publishes this <title>Revue Coloniale</title>, and that this Review has cited <persName ref="#ADp">M. Alexandre Dumas</persName> among its collaborators.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <floatingText>
                        <body>
                            <div>
                                <head>Mr. Editor of the <title>Revue des Colonies.</title></head>
                                <p>“Would you mind correcting in one of your next issues an error which I see committed in my regard on the cover of the <title>Revue Coloniale</title>; they announce that they will be publishing poems by me in one of their upcoming issues. First of all, I write little poetry, except for the theater; and I did not promise anything to the <title>Revue Coloniale</title>, which did not ask me for anything. All my sympathies, on the contrary, are instinctively and nationally for the adversaries of the principles defended by the Gentlemen of the <title>Revue Coloniale</title>; this is what I wish to be made perfectly clear, not only in France, but wherever I have brothers in race and friends of color.<ptr target="#mock1"/></p>
                                <lb/>
                                <closer>Please accept, etc. <lb/> <signed>A. DUMAS</signed>
                                </closer>
                            </div>
                        </body>
                    </floatingText>
                </div>
                <div>
                <head>BIOGRAPHY.
                </head>
                <head>VASSA<ptr target="#mock2"/></head>
                <p><persName ref="#Equ">Olaudad-Equiano, or Gustave Vassa</persName> (better known by that name), was born in <placeName ref="#Esk">Essaka</placeName>, a charming and fertile valley, a great distance from the coast and the capital of Bénier<ptr target="#mock3"/>. At the age of</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <closer>5th Year.										13</closer>
        </body>
        <back>
            <xi:include href="RdCv5n6p13-notes.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="entities.xml"/>
        </back>
    </text>
</TEI>
