<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xml:id="RdCv1n1-en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Revue des Colonies V.1 N°1 (selection in English translation)</title>
                <editor>Maria Beliaeva Solomon</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <xi:include href="shared/editionStmt.xml"/>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Information about the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <front>
          <pb n="1" facs="v1n1p1"/>
            <titlePage>
                <titlePart type="main"><seg>REVUE</seg><lb/>DES<lb/><seg>COLONIES,</seg></titlePart>
                <titlePart type="sub">MONTHLY COMPENDIUM<ptr target="#n13FA"/><lb/> OF
                    POLITICS, ADMINISTRATION, JUSTICE, INSTRUCTION AND COLONIAL CUSTOMS,</titlePart>
                <byline>BY A <orgName ref="#SHC">SOCIETY OF MEN OF COLOR</orgName></byline>
                <byline>DIRECTED BY <persName ref="#CB">C.-A. BISSETTE</persName>.<lb/></byline>
                <docEdition>N°1<lb/>July.</docEdition>
                <docImprint><pubPlace><settlement>PARIS</settlement>,<lb/> AT THE OFFICE OF THE REVUE DES COLONIES,<lb/>46, RUE NEUVE-SAINT-EUSTACHE</pubPlace> <lb/> <date>1834</date>.</docImprint>
            </titlePage>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div>
               <pb n="3" facs="v1n1p3"/>
                <head><seg>REVUE</seg><lb/>DES <lb/><seg>COLONIES</seg></head>
                <div xml:id="prospectus">
                    <head rend="bold">Prospectus.</head>
                    <p> As of now, the colonies, generally speaking, only know of the great
                        principles of philanthropy in theory; of freedom in action, nothing at all. </p>
                    <p> The suffering and oppressed classes appeal and fight relentlessly, always in
                        vain. To stimulate the feeble good will to which our rulers limit
                        themselves, it is necessary to compile the just complaints that arise from
                        all sides. These claims, these grievances, to be successful, must receive
                        the greatest publicity: this is the object of our <bibl type="periodical"
                                ><title ref="#RdC">Revue</title></bibl>
                    </p>
                    <p> The debate floor <emph>today</emph> is no longer enough; petitions are
                        adjourned by the calculated negligence of rapporteurs or pushed back by the 
                        insolent agendas of the day. On the other hand, colonial authorities, always
                        disposed in favor of the privileged, cleverly evade the ministers' prescriptions. Against this hitherto successful tactic
                        of the partisans of aristocracy and privilege, it is necessary to finally
                        engage the power of public opinion, enlightened by a discussion always wise,
                        always true, but energetic and never timid, of the causes, whatever they may
                        be, which hinder the desirable fusion of the diverse populations of the
                            colonies.<ptr target="#n4F2A"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> For this purpose, a specialized journal is founded under the title of <bibl
                            type="periodical"><title ref="#RdC"> Revue des Colonies</title></bibl>,
                        with <persName ref="#CB">Mr. Bissette</persName> as director. </p>
                    <pb n="4" facs="v1n1p4"/>
                    <p> This journal is not only dedicated to all that concerns the colonies,
                        considered as a source of news and interesting facts apt to occupy the
                        leisure of the reader, but it devotes itself entirely to the political,
                        intellectual, moral and industrial interests of colonists of either
                            color.<ptr target="#n6CEA"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> Nothing that concerns the French colonies in particular will be omitted from
                        this monthly publication. The government, the administration, and the justice
                        system will be examined here with respect to both their actions and their
                        persons; for it is the latter that too often determines the spirit and
                        the manner in which populations are either oppressed or well looked
                        after.</p>
                    <p> The civil, political, and social rights of the two free classes, which,
                        having been hitherto divided, ought to be united, will here be advanced and
                        supported with indefatigable zeal. </p>
                    <p> The great question of the abolition of slavery, the cornerstone of liberty,
                        will here be treated with the most conscientious care and the most ardent
                        love of equality and of the general good.<ptr target="#n79DB"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>Arbitrariness and partiality will here be brought to face the court of public
                        opinion with no distinction between persons. The weak will find here support
                        and protection, the oppressor, punishment, the official, warranted blame for
                        his illegal acts, but respect for his person. </p>
                    <p> The <title>Revue des Colonies</title> will also concern itself with all the
                        changes made or projected in the legislation that governs foreign colonies
                        and inevitably affects our own in a powerful way.<ptr target="#n5699"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> National interests, in relation to the possession of
                            <placeName ref="#Alg">Algiers</placeName>, will find in the <title>Revue des
                            Colonies</title> a devoted and independent outlet.<ptr target="#n6ED7"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> Numerous and knowledgeable correspondents ensure that readers find as much
                        variety as edification in the articles of the <title>Revue des
                            Colonies.</title>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <pb/>
                <div xml:id="declaration">
                  <pb n="5" facs="v1n1p5"/>
                    <head>DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES.</head>
                    <p> The <title>Revue des Colonies</title> believes it must, above all, indicate
                        by what principles it will offer judgment upon men and things.<ptr
                            target="#n3E34"/> In its estimation, '89, in the immortal Declaration
                        of Rights voted by the <orgName ref="#AN">National Assembly</orgName>, laid
                        the future foundations of all truly democratic institutions; this is why we
                        inscribe this <title>Declaration</title> at the beginning of this
                        compendium: these are the tables of our law. </p>
                    <epigraph>
                        <cit>
                            <quote>The rights of men had been misunderstood, insulted for centuries;
                                they have been restored for all mankind by this
                                    <title>Declaration</title>, which will forever remain a rallying
                                cry against oppressors, and a law for legislators themselves. </quote>
                            <bibl type="legal">(Address of the <orgName>National Assembly</orgName>
                                to the French People, 11 February 1790.)</bibl>
                        </cit>
                    </epigraph>
                </div>
                <div>
                 <div>
                    <head rend="bold">Excerpt</head>
                    <head>FROM THE MINUTES OF THE <orgName>NATIONAL ASSEMBLY</orgName> OF AUGUST 20,
                        21, 22, 23, 24, 26 AND OCTOBER 1st, 1789.</head>
                                <head>DECLARATION OF THE RIGHTS OF MAN IN SOCIETY.<ptr
                                        target="#n7767"/></head>
                                <p>The representatives of the French People, formed into a National
                                    Assembly, considering ignorance, forgetfulness or contempt of
                                    the rights of man to be the only causes of public misfortunes
                                    and the corruption of Governments, have resolved to set forth,
                                    in a solemn Declaration, the natural, unalienable and sacred
                                    rights of man, to the end that this Declaration, constantly
                                    present to all members of the body politic, may remind them
                                    unceasingly of their rights and their duties; to the end that
                                    the acts of the legislative power and those of the executive
                                    power, since they may be continually compared with the aim of
                                    every political institution, may thereby be the more respected;
                                    to the end that the demands of the citizens, founded henceforth
                                    on simple and incontestable principles, may always be directed
                                    toward the maintenance of the Constitution and the happiness of
                                    all. </p>
                                <pb n="6" facs="v1n1p6"/>
                                <p> In consequence whereof, the National Assembly recognizes and
                                    declares, in the presence and under the auspices of the Supreme
                                    Being, the following Rights of Man and of the Citizen. </p>
                                <p xml:id="art1">Article 1.-Men are born and remain free and equal in rights.
                                    Social distinctions may be based only on considerations of the
                                    common good.</p>
                                <p>2.- The aim of every political association is the preservation of
                                    the natural and imprescriptible rights of man. These rights are
                                    Liberty, Property, Safety and Resistance to Oppression.</p>
                                <p xml:id="art3">3.-The source of all sovereignty lies essentially in the Nation.
                                    No corporate body, no individual may exercise any authority that
                                    does not expressly emanate from it.</p>
                                <p>4.- Liberty consists in being able to do anything that does not
                                    harm others: thus, the exercise of the natural rights of every
                                    man has no bounds other than those that ensure to the other
                                    members of society the enjoyment of these same rights. These
                                    bounds may be determined only by Law.</p>
                                <p><gap reason="accidental" unit="number" extent="1"
                                        /><supplied>5.-</supplied> The Law has the right to forbid
                                    only those actions that are injurious to society. Nothing that
                                    is not forbidden by Law may be hindered, and no one may be
                                    compelled to do what the Law does not ordain.</p>
                                <p><choice>
                                        <sic>5.-</sic>
                                        <corr>6.-</corr>
                                    </choice>The Law is the expression of the general will. All
                                    citizens have the right to take part, personally or through
                                    their representatives, in its making. It must be the same for
                                    all, whether it protects or punishes. All citizens, being equal
                                    in its eyes, shall be equally eligible to all high offices,
                                    public positions and employments, according to their ability,
                                    and without other distinction than that of their virtues and
                                    talents.</p>
                                <p>7.- No man may be accused, arrested or detained except in the
                                    cases determined by the Law, and following the procedure that it
                                    has prescribed. Those who solicit, expedite, carry out, or cause
                                    to be carried out arbitrary orders must be punished; but any
                                    citizen summoned or apprehended by virtue of the Law, must give
                                    instant obedience; resistance makes him guilty.</p>
                                <p> 8.- The Law must prescribe only the punishments that are
                                    strictly and evidently necessary; and no one may be punished
                                    except by virtue of a Law drawn up and promulgated before the
                                    offense is committed, and legally applied.</p>
                                <p>9.- As every man is presumed innocent until he has <pb n="7" facs="v1n1p7"/>
                                    been declared guilty, if it should be considered necessary to
                                    arrest him, any undue harshness that is not required to secure
                                    his person must be severely curbed by Law.</p>
                                <p>10. - No one may be disturbed on account of his opinions, even
                                    religious ones, as long as the manifestation of such opinions
                                    does not interfere with the established Law and Order.</p>
                                <p>11.- The free communication of ideas and of opinions is one of
                                    the most precious rights of man. Any citizen may therefore
                                    speak, write and publish freely, except what is tantamount to
                                    the abuse of this liberty in the cases determined by Law.</p>
                                <p>12.- To guarantee the Rights of Man and of the Citizen a public
                                    force is necessary; this force is therefore established for the
                                    benefit of all, and not for the particular use of those to whom
                                    it is entrusted.</p>
                                <p>13. For the maintenance of the public force, and for
                                    administrative expenses, a general tax is indispensable; it must
                                    be equally distributed among all citizens, in proportion to
                                    their ability to pay.</p>
                                <p>14. All citizens have the right to ascertain, by themselves, or
                                    through their representatives, the need for a public tax, to
                                    consent to it freely, to watch over its use, and to determine
                                    its proportion, basis, collection and duration.</p>
                                <p>15. Society has the right to ask a public official for an
                                    accounting of his administration.</p>
                                <p>16. Any society in which no provision is made for guaranteeing
                                    rights or for the separation of powers, has no Constitution.</p>
                                <p xml:id="art17">17.- Since the right to Property is inviolable and sacred, no one
                                    may be deprived thereof, unless public necessity, legally
                                    ascertained, obviously requires it, and just and prior indemnity
                                    has been paid.</p>
                                <closer> Excerpt from the minutes of the <orgName>National
                                        Assembly</orgName>, October 1, 1789. <lb/>Collated true to
                                    the original. <signed>Signed MOUNIER, president; Viscount DE
                                        MIRABEAU, DEMEUNIER, BUREAU DE Pusy, Bishop DE NANCY,
                                        FAYDEL, Abbot of EYMAR, secretaries. </signed>
                                </closer>
                            </div>
                    <pb n="8" facs="v1n1p8"/>
                    <p>All of the principles of '89 are in this declaration; and, whatever one does,
                        there is in these principles, which the French revolution, by its republican
                        and imperial armies, has sown acrossed the land of <placeName>Europe</placeName>, and by its books everywhere in the universe, a
                        power which cannot be suppressed. </p>
                    <p>Certainly, if a man should be reminded of anything, it is his rights, which
                        aristocracies may well succeed in making obsolete here and there, but to
                        which the future belongs.</p>
                    <p>We ask that we compare the present state of our legislation with this page of
                        justice and liberty, that we examine whether the laws that are made for us
                        are in conformity with the principles of this declaration, which must be
                        forever, according to the fine expression of the <orgName>National
                            Assembly</orgName>, <emph>the law of the legislators
                        themselves</emph>. And if this examination clearly shows that the government,
                        whatever it may be, is not founded on this one equitable basis — the
                        enforcement of the rights of all — those who, like us and with the
                            <orgName>National Assembly</orgName>, will be convinced that
                            <emph>ignorance, forgetfulness or contempt for the rights of man are the
                            only causes of public misfortunes and the corruption of
                            governments</emph>, will triumphantly conclude that all the evil of the
                        present situation, in the colonies as everywhere, is absolutely a result of
                        this ignorance, of this forgetfulness or of this contempt, we cannot
                        precisely say which, as much on the part of the rulers as on that of the
                        governed.</p>
                    <closer>
                        <emph>The director</emph>, <signed><persName ref="#CB"
                            >BISSETTE</persName>.</signed>
                    </closer>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="regime">
                    <head>A LOOK AT THE COLONIAL REGIME AND ITS EFFECTS.</head>
                    <p>The deplorable events of Grand'Anse, <ptr target="#n590A"/>
                        <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName> have echoed through every
                        newspaper. Some, inspired by the authorities, in whose eyes all that is
                        emancipation becomes an object of terror, have presented this affair in an
                        unfavorable light to those who have limited themselves to passive
                            resistance.<ptr target="#n684A"/> Others, more benevolent, and above
                        all, more impartial, were careful not to pass premature judgment on a matter
                        of this nature: they knew that passion exaggerates both evil and good, and
                        that one should not <pb n="9" facs="v1n1p9"/>rush to adopt the words of a powerful and
                        often unjust party. </p>
                    <p>We too will attend to this matter, but by prefacing it with all the
                        considerations necessary to draw the correct conclusions.</p>
                    <p>These facts, which seem to us hardly believable, are repeated every day with
                        impunity in our colonies. And how could it not be so, when the men charged
                        with maintaining the laws are those most interested in violating them!
                        Arbitrariness is therefore only the sad corollary of a state of affairs
                        whose origins date back to a time of conquest, plunder and brutal violence.
                        We know that this arbitrariness exists; philosophy has decried it; power
                        itself seems to reject a shameful solidarity, and yet nothing real has been
                        done to put an end to it. Everything has been deceit and lies, from the
                        illusory measures against the slave trade, to the laws which seem to grant
                        men of color the rights of citizens, and a justice which one could not
                        truthfully represent scales in the hand.</p>
                    <p>These causes, which, deriving from the overall regime of the colonies, would seem foreign to the events of Grand'Anse, to which we will attend more particularly, 
                    <ptr target="#n65C6"/> are nevertheless attached to them by a multitude of threads:
                        for nothing in the fate of peoples, as in that of men, is isolated, and the
                        actual effects are often produced by causes lost to the depths of time.</p>
                    <p>The colonies too, despite their distance from the motherland, felt the
                        effects of the great political commotion which regenerated <placeName>France</placeName>. A long subjugation, largely exploited by
                        the aristocracy, had not been able to paralyze hearts so much that they did
                        not feel warmed by the rays of the sun of freedom. Men of color especially,
                        more advantaged than the unfortunate slaves, turned their eyes towards
                        France with love and confidence; they felt that each link which fell from
                        the chains of old Europe was for them a pledge of emancipation. The
                        emblazoned nobility, elevated to the rank of people, offered an edifying
                        lesson to the nobility of the skin,<ptr target="#n2BFD"/> which did not
                        even possess the prestige of the former's personal accomplishments. The
                        destruction of one was the sure guarantee of the destruction of the other.
                        Was not the emancipation of the people, who had long suffered the bondage <pb n="10" facs="v1n1p10"/>of the field, also a sign of freedom for the slaves? There was
                        therefore in the colonies what is still there today, an absurd aristocracy
                        clinging to its privileges and willing to go to any length to preserve them,
                        and on the other hand a population full of verve, of energy, beginning to
                        understand its rights and its dignity. </p>
                    <p>Such, then, was the position of the colonies when the July revolution,<ptr
                            target="#n9F29"/> so rich in prospects, made conceivable for a moment
                        the awakening of France. The new government, carried along, no doubt in
                        spite of itself, by the force of circumstance, not daring to lift the veil
                        which hid its ulterior motives, finally bowing before public opinion which
                        had just had its impact felt, erased the word <emph>regulations</emph> from
                        the article of the charter concerning the colonies. It declared that the
                        colonies would be governed by special <emph>laws</emph><ptr target="#n3257"
                        />. This tacit recognition of abuses of all kinds, originating in the
                        corrupted system of ordinences, stoked the hopes of those who could still
                        put some faith in ministers' promises. It was because they did not believe
                        that a government born of democracy could so quickly forget its origin; they
                        did not comprehend that the preservation of titles of nobility, of a
                        so-called upper chamber, and above all of an exaggerated civil list were
                        milestones laid down by the nascent power to constitute itself on bases
                        similar to that which the popular arm had just crushed. Did not the
                        preservation of the titled nobility in the motherland,<ptr target="#n917D"/> and the addition that was made to it of a Turcarets aristrocracy,<ptr
                            target="#n9C9A"/> clearly impart to the colonies that, except for a few
                        slight adjustments, their aristocracy of skin would be preserved along with
                        most of its privileges.</p>
                    <p>Indeed these fine particular <emph>laws</emph> were rendered so illusory as
                        to match the ordinances' arbitrariness,<ptr target="#n332A"/> differing from
                        them only by the hypocrisy of the name. For example, is not the electoral
                        law, establishing the political rights of whites and of men of color, a work
                        of perfidious deception? On the <placeName ref="#BrB">isle of
                            Bourbon</placeName> and of <placeName ref="#Cay">Cayenne</placeName>,
                        where the whites are in overwhelming majority, the electoral qualification
                        and eligibility are fixed at a lower rate, for there is no fear of
                        competition; but in the colonies of <placeName ref="#GP">Guadeloupe
                        </placeName> and <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, where the
                        population of color, quite numerous, is of <pb n="11" facs="v1n1p11"/>average wealth, the
                        tax is preemptively raised to an unattainable level. Is there anything more
                        perfidious, I would even say more odiously ironic, than to thus concede the
                        right while prohibiting the means. Would it not have been truer to declare
                        outright that only whites could vote?<ptr target="#n0490"/></p>
                    <p>It became difficult, in the presence of this law of political organization,
                        creating or rather sanctioning a privilege, to allow for the action of the
                        popular will. The national guard, that
                        admirable institution of the métropole,<ptr target="#n5F16"/> had a pale
                        imitation in the colonies, where both the name and the democratic element of
                        election were carefully banished.</p>
                    <p>If France has a national guard, the colonies have a militia whose officers,
                        appointed by the governor, are generally taken from the white population and
                        from among a few men of color. These, to keep a rank obtained by favor,
                        devote themselves unquestioningly to the governor and become his
                        accomplices. We hasten to say that, among those promoted, we count friends
                        who have not wavered in their political opinions, but not all of them are
                        so. When power makes itself odious by its partiality, it always corrupts the
                        men who make themselves its supporters. What bonds can indeed unite men who
                        find themselves in a position so false as the colonial militia and its
                        leaders? Trust? It does not exist. Fraternity? it would be vain to search
                        for it there. So there remains only force, and it is indeed felt
                        everyday.</p>
                    <p>In the judicial system, abuses abound, and they are always to the advantage
                        of the aristocratic class. The royal courts and the magistrates' courts are
                        constituted in such a way as to let the whites become judges and parties in
                        their own cause. Finally, despite the very text of the charter, provost
                        courts can still bloody the soil of the colonies by legally assassinating
                        the innocent people they want to get rid of.</p>
                    <p>Well! in the presence of this boundless arbitrariness, leaning on their
                        numerous privileges, the whites groan and complain that the government has
                        dared to touch the holy ark of their power, by diminishing some of their
                        privileges. Political rights, they possess them all; the judicial power is
                        in their hands; law enforcement, they<pb n="12" facs="v1n1p12"/> direct and command it; but
                        it is not enough to suit their wounded pride. A principle, admittedly
                        without application, has been issued; the word equality was spoken, was it
                        not enough to offend those selfish and hard hearts for whom every
                        independent man who is not part of their league is but a worthless
                        rebellious slave?<ptr target="#n3701"/> Men of color, on the contrary,
                        confident in the government's feeble pledges of good will, waited patiently
                        for better days perfecting their political education so as to wield the
                        influence that they are entitled to in their country by their rights and
                        numbers. And what do they really want that is not wise and reasonable?
                        Placed in their land in the same position as the third estate in France
                        before the revolution, they then ask what this order commanded: liberty and
                        equality. But they are dealing with privileged people who are even more
                        tenacious than the nobility and clergy of France. These at least did not
                        have the impudence to deny the title of men to their adversaries.<ptr
                            target="#n8508"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>By what means, then, could the privileged recover the integrity of their
                        privileges? To ask the government for them was impossible, they would have
                        been told to bide their time; that the compromise was only a matter of
                        painful necessity; that, moreover, the liberties granted to the mulattoes
                        were purely illusory, being limited in reality to a few slight concessions
                        of sociability.<ptr target="#n6759"/> And furthermore these same concessions
                        often bend according to the whims of the aristocracy. These answers, which
                        would satisfy less impatient, and above all less prideful men, would have
                        deeply wounded those imperious masters whose despotism is exercised without
                        control over unfortunate slaves. It was therefore necessary to employ all
                        means, even calumny, to subjugate the class of color and crush it.<ptr
                            target="#n7A20"/> It had to be represented as factious, turbulent,
                        having sworn to destroy the whites and stopping at nothing, not murder, not
                        arson, to accomplish this. It is so easy to slander men who are not allowed
                        to defend themselves! To find guilty the enemy that one judges oneself! And
                        then the colonies also count among their ranks men who know how to create
                        conspiracies, foment them, cause them to arise at the right time, in order
                        to take advantage of them in their own interest. And what does it really
                        matter that the worthless blood of a few negroes comes to redden the ground!
                        What does it matter if a mulatto's head rolls on<pb n="13" facs="v1n1p13"/> the scaffold!
                        Mere trifles, when you consider the glorious result expected of it; that is,
                        the bondage of the many for the benefit of the few. Besides, the métropole
                        offers a few examples which would seem to authorize the colonies in this
                        Machiavellianism.</p>
                    <p>And so we have seen the birth of these imaginary plots, these conflagrations
                        whose frequency during certain periods bespeaks frightful mysteries.
                        Innocents have been accused, thrown into dungeons, tortured, shot without
                        pity when they allowed themselves a few complaints. Neither sex nor age
                        could soften these ferocious men who subject their slaves to the most
                        sophisticated cruelties, and their gold, thrown at the heads of the
                        proconsuls of the great nation, hides large stains of blood from their
                        eyes.</p>
                    <p>Ah! if some day an eloquent pen tearing the funereal veil which covers our
                        colonies, would retrace the history of domination of the possessors of
                        men; if it evoked from the depths of their tombs the sad victims who are
                        heaped there every day, never would a country defiled by tyranny offer such
                        horrible pages.<ptr target="#n4C92"/> All that we read of the Mésences, the
                        Caligulas, the Louis XIs,<ptr target="#n5DA0"/> all that our hearts refuse
                        to believe as too degrading for humanity, finds itself surpassed in the
                        nineteenth century by overseas Frenchmen. But these horrible scenes of
                        despotism have no place here, elsewhere we will reveal them by throwing the
                        names of their infamous authors among the ignominies of history. </p>
                </div>
                
                  <div xml:id="affair">
                       <head>THE GRAND'ANSE AFFAIR</head>
<p>While the public prosecutor’s office of <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName> laboriously gives birth to what it calls <rs type="event"><emph>the insurrection of Grand'Anse</emph></rs>, the insurrection of Grand'Anse, the metropolitan government’s attention is drawn to those deplorable events by the complaint of the principal victims addressed to the Council of State. The plaintiffs are, among others, the heirs of the unfortunate <persName><emph>Lorville</emph></persName>, who fell pierced by seven bullets under a volley of musketry ordered to stop his escape; the heirs of <persName><emph>Fréjus</emph></persName>, left for dead under the blows of a <persName>Lasserre</persName> and since deceased as a result of the violence exercised against him; the heirs of Maurie<persName><emph>Maurice</emph></persName> <pb n="14" facs="v1n1p14"/>killed with his wife, and his daughter murdered by a volley shot through their hut; <persName><emph>Joseph Albert</emph></persName>, deported in <date>1823</date>, wounded in that other shooting carried out on the prisoners of the Bonafon purgerie, through the window gratings, etc., etc. </p>
<p>Admittedly, such victims, immolated not in a conflict, not in an armed struggle between the authorities and such and such part of the population, but murdered in their prison, in their home after having surrendered on the faith of fallacious promises; such victims raising their voices to the mother country seemed worthy of some attention on the part of the ministry.</p>
<p>With what painful indignation will our fellow citizens of the colonies be seized when they learn how the <persName ref="#GVD">the Minister of the Navy</persName> welcomed their request to the <persName ref="#LP"><roleName>king</roleName></persName> in his council for authorization to prosecute the authors or culprits of these saturnalia of arbitrariness and bloodshed! The <persName><roleName>minister</roleName></persName> to whom the request was communicated, according to custom, contented himself with the following short and disdainful observations: <q>I will not discuss the facts because the majority of the plaintiffs are included in the trial currently being heard in <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>. The <bibl type="periodical"><title ref="#MU">Moniteur</title></bibl> of <date>March 17</date> has moreover published a <emph>report emanating from <persName ref="#EH"><roleName>the governor</roleName></persName></emph> (that is to say, the person whom the plaintiffs accuse) which, given the confidence he is owed, cannot be entered alongside the account of individuals compromised in the accusation.</q></p>
<p>Then, soon shedding his affected respect for the position of the accused,<persName ref="#GVD"> <roleName> the minister</roleName></persName> ends his letter by calling them <emph>factious men</emph>, rehashing in banal and hackneyed phrases the commonplaces of the day: <q> That it would be dangerous to entertain their <emph>recriminations</emph> at a time when so many and such culpable attempts are directed against public peace. Such is the opinion of the Department of the Navy on the recourse of plaintiffs to the Council of State. We like to believe that this high jurisdiction will follow inspirations that are more generous, more equitable, more friendly to humanity.</q></p>
<p>Yes, indeed, some of the plaintiffs–that is to say <emph>three</emph>, not the <emph>majority</emph>–are destined to feature in the sad trial which is currently being staged in <placeName>Martinique</placeName>; but the others, but those who died unarmed, prisoners, under the soldiers’ bullets, those will not go to the assizes. How can one counter <pb n="15" facs="v1n1p15"/>in cold blood the complaints of their wives and children with this cruel denial of justice? Whatever the result of the trial, even if it were to prove the existence of the alleged conspiracy, could it ever justify the local government’s massacre of conspirators who had been captured, disarmed and who were held prisoners, kept in sight, besieged on all sides by law enforcement? will it absolve local authorities for letting these unfortunate victims fall under a rain of murderous lead?
</p>
<p>We know today in France what procedure was initiated because of the events of Grand'Anse. We have before us a printed copy of the order for remand to the assizes, issued by the indictment chamber, against 117 defendants. This document notes what we have just said, that only three of those who have addressed a request to the Council of State are referred to the Assizes of <placeName>Saint-Pierre</placeName>. Saint-Pierre. This decision also authentically establishes the facts stated in the request, and which the <persName ref="#GVD"><roleName>Minister of the Navy</roleName></persName> disdains to discuss, in particular <emph>the shooting carried out on <persName>Lorville</persName> and two other prisoners fleeing with him, by express order of the captain in command</emph> (pages 51 and 55 of the indictment). As for the massacre of the <persName><emph>Maurice</emph></persName> family, it is acknowledged, albeit in a somewhat distorted account, by this same <title>Moniteur</title> of <date>March 17</date> Moniteur of March 17, whose sincerity seems less doubtful than that of the plaintiffs, but from which nevertheless the Minister has removed certain, overly clumsy, passages of the <persName ref="#EH"><roleName>governor</roleName></persName>'s report. Are facts so incontestable unworthy of the solicitude of the government? do they not deserve examination, investigation, adversarial discussion with the <persName ref="#GVD"><roleName>Minister</roleName></persName>? There are a host of others also specified in the request, all those who denounce to the métropole for the hundredth time the systematic oppression of the classes of color, the daily provocations directed against them, the continued denial of all their rights in defiance of the laws that grant them, finally all those others which give true color to the events of <placeName>la Grand'Anse</placeName>. But what does it matter! all these facts of high political and social importance will be omitted, concealed, denied if necessary, and in all cases excused. What the so-called official and authentic relations of the 
<title><emph>Moniteur</emph></title> will show to the colonies, to France, is <emph>one hundred and <pb n="16" facs="v1n1p16"/>seventeen conspiratorrs</emph> appearing in court under the weight of a 300-page charge, all accused of conspiracy, for the government of <placeName>Martinique</placeName> needs one; then each one in particular accused of having looted two jars of tafia and two jars of rum from <persName><emph>Seguinot</emph></persName>; or from <persName><emph>Desmadrelles</emph></persName>, soap, candles, a horse's currycomb; or from <persName><emph>Lereynerie</emph></persName>, a bottle of jenever (pages 85 and 86 of the order for reference). And all this printed by the government of the colony over 200 pages, pompously titled, by the most ignorant of magistrates, <rs type="event"><emph>Insurrection of Grand'Anse</emph></rs>.</p>
<p>What of the permanent conspiracy against the rights and personal safety of the population of color! the permanent insurrection of the whites against the laws of the métropole, every day shamelessly spurned by these colonists from the north of the colony, made infamous by the mass proscription of 1823, by their declaration to the government that they would never recognize men of color as their equals! What is being done about these conspiracies that reappear every day, always going unpunished?</p>
<p>Wretched colonies! will it ever be your fate to pointlessly show your wounds to the motherland, only for our incredulous rulers to not even deign probe it with their fingers!</p>
         </div>
<div xml:id="speech"><head>A WORD ON THE SPEECH DELIVERED BY MR. ISAMBERT AT THE SESSION OF THIS PAST MAY 8TH.</head>
<p>
If experience is the touchstone of all legislation, we cannot disagree that the organic law for the colonies promulgated in 1833 is essentially defective; for the results it has produced are detestable; <persName ref="#FI">Mr. Isambert</persName> demonstrated this abundantly. The commission charged with examining this law unanimously recognized, he tells us, that it was desirable that men of color be admitted to the colonial council. Well! With the exception of 
<placeName ref="#GF">French Guiana</placeName>, in each of our colonies and notably in the most important of all,  <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, this council was formed exclusively of white colonists. This fundamental flaw in composition is an insurmountable obstacle
</p><pb n="17" facs="v1n1p17"/>
<p>to the introduction of the reforms that the situation in our colonies urgently demands. In support of this assertion, Mr. Isambert cites a fact that is well worth repeating here: the governor of Martinique presented various draft royal ordinances to the colonial council regarding the reorganization of militias, the form and conditions of manumission, the advice to be given regarding municipal and judicial organization, etc. Here is how the council responded: <q>The colonial council pays tribute to the government's intentions on behalf of the king, but often the measures taken to achieve this goal, instead of attaining it, lead to disastrous results. We will immediately focus on the 1834 budget.</q> Frankly, is this not a clear rejection of the governor's proposals? Is this not telling him that his suggestions are not even worth considering? Therefore, without a second thought, the council will immediately move on to the budget. Does this display of disdain and directness not perfectly illustrate the aristocratic arrogance of our very high and mighty masters by <emph>right of whiteness</emph>?
</p>
<p>Vis-à-vis this impertinent response, the honorable deputy placed the generous words by which the colonial council of French Guiana not only promised its assistance in all the improvement projects presented by the governor, but even committed to initiating reforms on many points. Why were these proposals received so differently in one of the colonies compared to the other? It is because the 1833 law was even more restrictive in granting suffrage rights to people of color in Martinique and <placeName ref="#GP">Guadeloupe</placeName>, than to those residing in French Guiana.
</p>
<p><q>It wouldn't be the case,</q> dit Mr. Isambert, <q><emph>if a few men of color</emph> (I say some because I don't claim to want the classes, which have remained in complete isolation up to now, to have the same advantage as the Creole class), but again, if a few men of color were admitted to the colonial council.</q> One can see that the illustrious legal expert is here displaying a conciliatory attitude and playing a bit too nicely to the colonial aristocracy; therefore, it is our duty to protest against a </p><pb n="18" facs="v1n1p18"/>
<p>concession that would do nothing less than uphold privilege and be an attack on the great principle of equality.</p>
<p>We would regret it if one were to perceive even the shadow of a reproach in our words. We know all too well Mr. Isambert’s conscientious integrity and love of justice to find in this departure from a principle anything other than a momentary lapse. Moreover, Mr. Isambert's generous instincts quickly lead him back to common law. A few lines further, he indeed speaks out against the bias of the electoral system, which, out of ten voters, only admits one voter of color, even though the population of this class is three times that of the whites. This obviously denies every man of color access to the colonial council. On this matter, it is essential to return to the principle proclaimed by the Constituent Assembly, which granted the right to vote to every free man, aged twenty-five or older, owning property, or residing in the municipality for two years and paying a tax.</p>
<p>A portion of the discourse we are examining is dedicated to highlighting the monstrous flaws that abound in the judicial organization of Martinique, particularly in criminal justice. There, it seems that everything has been designed to deprive unfortunate litigants of any chance of acquittal. For instance, a court of assizes is composed of three counselors from the royal court and four members of the board of assessors, an institution that reflects the jury. All of them are exclusively selected from the white class. The four assessors are drawn by lot from a list of thirty members, but this list is further reduced by illnesses, absences, or any other impediments to twenty men per assize; the decision is made by the majority of votes from this kind of jury combined with that of the court, consisting of three judges. So, assuming unanimity from the court and the jury, the verdict is rendered with a number of votes lower than what is required of a jury in France; thus, four votes are sufficient in the colonies to pass a death sentence, whereas in France, eight are required for a criminal conviction, and English law, even more humane, demands unanimous jury agreement for all types of convictions.
</p>
<p>If you add to all of this the fact that in the colonies, men of
</p>
<pb n="19" facs="v1n1p19"/>
<p>color are constantly in competition with whites, and the intense and bitter animosities that divide them often lead to disputes that are interpreted as conspiracies, wouldn't you conclude that placing the sword of justice solely in the hands of the Creole inevitably turns it into an instrument of revenge and cruelty? That it leaves men of color at the mercy of their enemies, and to maintain such a state of affairs any longer would demonstrate a barbaric indifference to human life and a heinous disregard for the sacred laws of justice. Judicial reorganization is all the more urgent because, as a result of the sad events in Grand'Anse, a hundred and seventeen people are currently facing a capital charge.
</p>
</div>
 </div>
 <div xml:id="education">
<head>THE NEED FOR EDUCATION IN THE COLONIES</head>
<p>Men of color have owed improvements in their condition to the progress of public opinion. Since 1830, they have finally obtained the political rights that were denied to them for so long by individuals who were still interested in maintaining their subjugation. The humiliating distinctions that justly offended their wounded self-esteem and deprived them of the exercise of a natural right have finally disappeared. Today, they are an integral part of the great French family without restrictions. They are French citizens or eligible to become such. They can rightfully take pride in this qualification, which allows them to sit in the midst of the sovereign people, sharing in its sovereignty. However, they should also know that this civilization's blessing has imposed new responsibilities on them, the fulfillment of which is essential to maintaining the high status they have achieved through the triumph of freedom.
</p>
<p>It is to science that civilization owes its triumphant progress through the prejudices accumulated over the centuries. More precisely, civilization itself has been nothing more than the conquest of science. This is the noblest achievement of the human mind, and freedom, the offspring of civilization, could have no other origin than its mother. Science, civilization, and freedom are therefore inseparable correlates that presuppose and call each other, and they cannot exist separately.
</p>
<pb n="20" facs="v1n1p20"/>
<p>One would have to hold a deeply false idea of freedom to believe that it could securely establish itself in a country inhabited by men hostile to or, at the very least, apathetic towards education. The air one breathes in the abode of ignorance, prejudices, and shameful passions is mephitic to freedom. Freedom wants to be worshiped only by men with generous ideas and elevated sentiments who, through study, may appreciate her benefactions, offer her a pure and worthy devotion, and defend her against the attacks of her enemies.</p>
<p>Men of color must, therefore, abandon the independence they are so proud of today and the hope of acquiring any influence in the affairs of their country if they do not promote education among themselves. If a base and disastrous selfishness prevents them from making the necessary sacrifices for the education of their children in France. Today more than ever, they must feel this need: did not the colonial council of <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName> Martinique, in its first session, recently abolish the monitorial schools created by <persName ref="#AA">Mr. d'Argout</persName> during his time as Minister of the Navy?
</p>
<p>In the current state of affairs in the colonies, the political emancipation of men of color and their inclusion in the great French family is undoubtedly a cause for joy for each of them. However, what a source of humiliation do the majority of them find when, in the exercise of their new rights, they are put in contact with individuals well-versed in business and possessing specialized and diverse knowledge.</p>
<p>The education of women is even more backward than that of men. A regrettable silence, when they are in society, diminishes their charm and takes away what would be most appealing.</p>
<p>Don't place them alongside one of those Parisian women whose conversation is so lively, pleasant, and captivating. Nevertheless, nature has not been any less generous to the children of the colonies than to those of France: provide young individuals from the colonies with the same education, and soon the riches of their passionate imagination will be revealed. They will shine and captivate, just like our witty French women, with the diversity of their conversation and the indescribable charm of their remarks.</p>
 <p>We implore men of color not to judge our <pb n="21" facs="v1n1p21"/>criticisms as overly severe. It is a friendly voice that speaks to them. Let them heed the advice of men who constantly fight for the triumph of their cause and fear the possibility of their emancipation being incomplete or even fruitless. If men of color do not know how to break free from the state of torpor in which they languish, let them tremble in their apathetic ignorance. The links of their chains are scattered and broken, it is true, but an ambitious and bold hand could weld them together once more. A governor of the caliber of a <persName ref="#HF">Freycinet</persName> and a <persName ref="#FXD">Donzelot</persName>, can make them lose all their advantages. A prosecutor general as capable as <persName ref="#RL">RICHARD LUCY</persName>, can annul even the most firmly established concessions. Let them consider the events; they are far from offering them complete security.</p>
  <p>Their freedom will only be stable, unassailable, and their status as French citizens definitively secured when their children attend our schools and join various branches of the administration in large numbers. We will have confidence in their future only when we see them enrolling significant numbers of students in institutions of higher learning such as <orgName ref="#PO">Polytechnique</orgName>, <orgName ref="#StCyr">Saint-Cyr</orgName>, Medicine, Law, Commerce, and the Navy. It is then, and only then, that they will acquire the local influence and respect they covet and achieve the integration from which they are yet so far removed.</p>
   <p>As this is a matter of vital importance about which we could not possibly call the attention of our friends from the colonies too much, we will dedicate a series of articles on this same subject, and will propose a plan to realize our educational project and to neutralize in the same movement the efforts of the colonial aristocracy, which toward depriving the masses of education in order to better exploit them.</p></div>

   <div xml:id="question">
   <head>THE ELECTORAL QUESTION.</head>

   <p>A new question has arisen in electoral matters in the colonies: whether an unmarried woman can delegate her contributions to her legally recognized natural son.</p>
   <p>The Director General of the Interior in <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, acting as <pb n="22" facs="v1n1p22"/>prefect, has refused to recognize such delegation for the following reason:
   <q><p>To grant an unmarried woman the right to delegate would be to give an arbitrary extension to a provision that is already inherently exceptional by its nature.</p>
   <p>We have decided and hereby declare the following: <persName ref="#SUG">Mr. Sugnin (Philippe-Simon-Eudoxie)</persName> in the current state of affairs, cannot be registered on the electoral list of the 4th constituency. At <placeName ref="#FoR">Fort-Royal</placeName> (<placeName>Martinique</placeName>), <date>April 19th, 1833</date> <emph>Signed</emph> <persName ref="#RS">viscount ROSILY</persName>.</p></q></p>
   <p>The citizen affected by this decision neglected to appeal to the royal court for its revision within ten days of its notification, as stipulated by the law.</p>
   <p>Since this issue may arise frequently in the colonies, where a considerable number of unmarried women with legally recognized natural children can be found, we will provide observations against this decision in line with the spirit of the law.</p>
   <p>The argument upon which the decision we are contesting is based is the same one that was opposed to us during the Restoration when we argued, according to the law of February 5, 1817, that the delegation right belonged to divorced women and women legally separated, in favor of grandsons-in-law as well as sons-in-law.</p>
   <p>How did the <orgName ref="#CE">Council of State</orgName>,respond, given that it was dominated by the system of government of the time, which aimed to restrict rather than extend the exercise of political rights?</p>
 <p>Following a request presented by us on behalf of <persName ref="#AR">Mr. Aroux</persName>, now a deputy (February 11, 1824), it responded that <q>to grant the grandson-in-law a right that the law had limited to the son-in-law would be to give an arbitrary extension to an exceptional provision.</q> The 1831 law has put an end to this quibbling.</p> 
 <p>The 1817 law did not mention the adoptive mother; however, in a decision passed on September 9, 1830, the <orgName ref="#CRN">Royal Court of Nancy</orgName> ruled that she had the right to delegate. Since then, even though divorce has not been reinstated, upon our proposal in 1831, the <orgName ref="#CHD">Chamber of Deputies</orgName> has had no qualms admitting divorced women, like legally separated women, to the delegation right.</p><pb n="23" facs="v1n1p23"/>
 <p>Isn't the unmarried woman, who cannot exercise political rights attached to property ownership by herself, in exactly the same social position as the divorced woman and the legally separated woman?</p>
 <p>In <placeName>France</placeName>, In France, where morals are much stricter than in the colonies, one could consider <persName ref="#RS">Mr. Viscount de Rosily</persName> 's decision as a tribute to good morals.</p>
 <p>But he did not want to include this reason in his decree; it would have been a condemnation of an ingrained practice in the colonies, which magistrates like <persName ref="#DES">Mr. Dessalles</persName>, in the annals of <placeName>Martinique</placeName>, have argued is justified by the heat of the climate.</p>
 <p>We believe that, in addition to this consideration, there is another more compelling one. The number of voters is greatly restricted in the colonies, especially in the colored class. Far from there being a political motive to restrict the exercise of rights created by the 1833 law in favor of citizens of this class who could provide the desired property guarantees, the most vigorous support has been expressed for their expansion by the king's commissioners and the defenders of the law within the commission of which we were a part, but also within the chamber and beyond.</p>
 <p>The decision in question is therefore contrary to the spirit of the law, the spirit of all electoral legislation, which, when in doubt, seeks not to restrict the right but to expand it.
<placeName>Paris</placeName>, <date>July 2nd, 1834</date>.
<persName ref="#FI">ISAMBERT</persName>.</p>
<div><p><foreign><emph>Favores ampliandae.</emph></foreign> Nothing is more favorable than electoral law. The principle of delegation is the kind of equivalence that nature and the law establish between the mother and her children, <foreign><emph>una et eadem persona</emph></foreign>. If the law specifically mentions the widow and the legally separated woman, which implies marriage, it is because it refers to the most common case, but the law is indicative in this regard and not restrictive.
<persName ref="#OB">ODILON-BARROT.</persName></p><pb n="24" facs="v1n1p24"/></div>
</div>
<div xml:id="appeal">
<head>A <emph>DE FACTO</emph> FREEDMAN’S APPEAL.</head>

<p>A significant question regarding slavery has come before the <orgName ref="#CDC">Court of Cassation</orgName>.</p>
<p>Two young men were convicted by the Assize Court of  <placeName ref="#GF">French Guiana</placeName>, , along with a free man of color who did not file an appeal in cassation. Both of his co-accused were considered slaves throughout the proceedings. However, one of them, <persName ref="#CJ">Cyprien Jacquard</persName>, Cyprien Jacquard, argued that he was in a state of manumission because he had been bequeathed by his master to his emancipated mother, so as to provide him and other children with a means of livelihood.</p>
 <p>When this case was first presented, the <orgName>Court of Cassation</orgName> was struck by the odiousness of considering a child as a slave to his mother, whom she could potentially sell. It could happen that a mother was bequeathed by a master to her own son, and he might also be in a position to alienate her. Would such a reversal of the laws of nature be sanctioned by colonial legislation?
</p>
 <p>The court, in a ruling dated January 10, 1834, ordered that the facts be verified before making a decision on the appeal.</p>
 <p>As a result of the information gathered in compliance with this ruling, it was found that Jacquard's mother, upon gaining her freedom from her master, had received her children born of him, as well as her own mother, as part of her bequest. Subsequent to Jacquard's conviction, this woman made the required declarations at the civil registry office, as per the Ordinance of July 12, 1832, to obtain her son’s emancipation certificate.</p>
  <p>Given this situation, the Attorney General of the colony argued that Jacquard, the appellant in cassation, was not admissible to file an appeal in cassation. This was because, as per the colonial ordinance of July 20, 1828, Article 9, which the Criminal Procedure Code, since promulgated, does not override, slaves are prohibited from using this appeal, and Jacquard was still a slave at the time of the alleged crime and his conviction.</p>
  <p>At the hearing on June 26, <persName ref="#DEH">Counselor Dehaussy</persName> reported on this matter and, without examining the grounds for the appeal,<pb n="25" facs="v1n1p25"/>denied it in consideration of the state of slavery in which the appellants found themselves.</p>
  <p>This magistrate did not hide how distressing this situation was and how desirable it was for slavery to be declared incompatible with such intimate family relationships. He announced that, through his dispatch, the Attorney General assured that a bill regarding this incompatibility would be proposed in the session of the colonial council. However, he had not found a legal basis under which the Court of Cassation could release young Jacquard from the state of slavery in which he found himself.</p>
  <p><persName ref="#Parant">Mr. Parant</persName>, the Attorney General, concluded in this direction, invoking the admission Jacquard had made during his interrogation and the steps taken by his own mother to secure his emancipation.</p>
  <p>The admission recorded in his interrogation amounted to this:</p>
  <q><p>My name is Cyprien, also known as Jacquard; I am sixteen years old, and belong to the colored caste; I am a carpenter by profession; I belong to my mother, with whom I live in <placeName ref="#Cay">Cayenne</placeName>, where I was born.</p></q>
  <p>The court, in a ruling dated June 26, started from this point of fact and declared that there was no need to examine the merits of the appeal.</p>
  <p>During its discussion of the case of the <emph>de facto</emph> freedman <persName ref="#Louisy">Louisy</persName>, this court had seemed to us to better understand its high mission. </p>
  <p>It had judged that freedom is a right and that slavery should be confined within the strict limits granted it by the law, and that one should not treat as a slave someone who has de facto ceased to be one. Consequently, despite the colonial ordinances that obliged de facto freedmen in risk of being declared and sold as slaves for the benefit of the colonial domain, to produce their freedom papers, the court, focusing only on the law and the fact of freedom, declared Louisy’s appeal admissible.</p>
  <p>Was this not the occasion to render a similar ruling? Neither in Roman legislation nor in the <bibl type="legal"><title ref="#CN">Code Noir</title></bibl> (the edict of 1689) do we find consecrated such immorality, by which a father or<pb n="26" facs="v1n1p26"/>mother can become, arbitrarily, the property of their child. For, with such a doctrine, one would be obliged to tolerate that they sell the authors of their days in the market and receive the price. The Romans also abolished the ancient law that gave the father the right of life and death over all members of his family.</p>
  <p>The Code Noir allows for several cases where freedom results as of right from a status incompatible with slavery. This includes the case where a master has appointed a slave as his executor or as a guardian for his children.</p>
  <p></p>
   <p>How can one reconcile the status of being a son with that of being a slave to his mother? A son, according to natural law and the civil code published in the colonies, is bound by duties entirely different from those of a slave towards his mother.</p>
   <p>The mother also has particular duties towards her child. If this child becomes unable to provide for their subsistence, is she not obligated to nourish them? And how could such a law not be above the unjust law of slavery?</p>
   <p>It is regrettable that the Court of Cassation left this important question without resolution and only focused on the apparent fact. By judging in this manner, did it not violate Article 7 of the 1832 ordinance, which ensures that those who are de facto free have the benefit of an appeal in cassation?</p>
   <p>In declaring that he belonged to his mother, did not young Cyprien Jacquard prove, by that fact alone, that he had no master, and that there existed between him and his mother nothing but the natural and civic bond?</p></div>

   <div xml:id="traits">
   <head>TRAITS OF CRUELTY.</head>
   
   <p>It would be a lengthy story to recount the deeds of revolting cruelty that some slave owners in our colonies inflict upon the unfortunate slaves. Every day, torn by the whip of the overseer, deprived of their coarse sustenance, they slowly perish in incessant torment; only greed and never humanity sometimes hold back these <pb n="27" facs="v1n1p27"/>cruel masters who fear losing a venal price with the death of a slave. But when the slave, crippled or old, can no longer provide the same services, when his presumed profit on the plantation no longer exceeds the expenses he incurs, oh, then! No consideration can hold them back anymore, and just as one breaks an old, disabled piece of furniture, so do they mercilessly cause to perish the man they tore from his family when he was young.</p>
    <p>Sometimes, a whim, a resurgence of barbarity seizes a master, and no matter what potential prejudice such atrocious satisfaction might possibly bring him, he has a man, his peer, his equal, sacrificed. These acts of cold cruelty are so far from our mores that we, born in the colonies, cannot comprehend them. Often, an honorable skepticism guards us against the accounts of our correspondents. Would to God that they were all false! We would be the first to proclaim them so, and our hearts would not be burdened by painful impressions.</p>
    <p>Here are two new facts to record in the long list of crimes that makes up colonial history. There we not only see a colonist committing a heinous murder, but another ordering it to be carried out by his slaves, thus demoralizing these unfortunate individuals who, at the risk of their lives, could not refuse the orders they received.</p>
    <p>In <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, un landowner in the <placeName>commune of La Rivière Pilote</placeName>, a landowner in the commune of La Rivière Pilote, apparently convinced that he had reason to complain about his slave Gabriel, summoned six slaves from his workshop on April 16 and ordered them to bring him Gabriel's head. The slaves promised obedience.</p>
    <p>Gabriel, unofficially informed of his master's intentions, went to see him and offered 3,535 francs for his redemption. The master replied that he would consider it. Although this reply was nothing short of satisfactory, the unfortunate Gabriel set about realizing his funds, and went to the market town of Le Marin to sell his flour. As he was leaving, six negroes ambushed him, drove him to the sugar mill, tied him to a calabash tree and killed him. One of the executioners then went to the owner, who, having heard the story of the murder, simply replied coldly: <q><emph>That is well</emph></q>.</p><pb n="28" facs="v1n1p28"/>
    <p>However, the planter, having gone to the place where Gabriel's mutilated corpse lay, couldn't stand the dreadful sight for long: he withdrew, and with the help of his sugar maker, spread the rumor that Gabriel had been killed by a mule. He sent word to the Commune's Commissar, but public rumor had beaten him to it, and the Commissar came with the Justice of the Peace and two doctors to perform an autopsy on the corpse. The type of death was then recognized, and among other wounds, a gunshot wound to the lower jaw. A report was drawn up and deposited at <placeName ref="#FoR">Fort-Royal</placeName>.</p>
    <p>In the same colony, in the commune of <placeName>Macouba</placeName>, a wealthy owner was accused by the public of killing his slaves. The public prosecutor went to the property and found an unfortunate woman lying lifeless. The master had cruelly castigated her, and she had expired under the lashes. To ascertain whether the corpse was still alive, the cruel master went so far as to pierce his victim's belly with a hot iron. The courts are investigating the case, but the colonist accused of the crime is on the run. The new governor, <persName ref="#EH">Mr. Halgan</persName>, has hastened to send details of this act of colonial monstrosity to the Ministry of the Navy.</p>
    <p>It is to be hoped that, in the interests of justice and humanity, such crimes will not go unpunished. The honor of the government and the salvation of the colony are at stake; for where the reign of justice ceases, the right of might and violence is born.  </p></div>
    <div xml:id="france">
    <head>FRANCE.</head>
    <head>PARIS.</head>
    <head>CONVOCATION OF THE CHAMBERS.</head>
    
    <p>The following ordinance is published in the <bibl type="periodical"><title ref="#MU">Moniteur</title></bibl> of <date>July 1</date>, dated <date>June 30</date> and countersigned by <persName ref="#THI">Mr. Thiers</persName> : </p>
    <q><p>Art. 1. The provision of our ordinance of May 25 of this year, which convened the Chamber of Peers and the Chamber of Deputies for August 20, 1834, is revoked.<pb n="29" facs="v1n1p29"/>Art. 2. The Chamber of Peers and the Chamber of Deputies are convened for the next July 31.</p></q>
    <p>The <title><emph>Moniteur</emph></title> publishes immediately after, but in the non-official section, the following communication which explains the significance of this measure:</p>
    <q><p>The meeting of the chambers was scheduled for August 20th next. It is now brought forward and set, by this day's ordinance, to July 31st. The king, who in August will be traveling to the southern provinces he has not yet visited, did not want to be absent at the time of the chambers' assembly. Furthermore, this assembly does not have its usual importance: it is convened for the execution of Article 42 of the Charter. However, the government cannot and should not commence their work at that time; no bills, no budget proposals could be ready. Besides, our parliamentary traditions fix the period for the chambers' work between the months of December and May, during the winter season. To begin them in the middle of summer would be an unfortunate departure from established customs. Three hundred deputies from the former chamber, now part of the new one, have already spent five months in Paris this year and could hardly return in July. It is, therefore, appropriate to postpone the work to the customary time. Consequently, after convening the chambers on July 31 and having them in session, the king, using the right of prorogation, will prorogue them until the end of the year to begin the important work of the new legislature at that time.</p></q>
     <p>Proroguing the chambers before they are constituted would be another outrage to add to all those we witness daily. The chambers cannot be prorogued before the new powers of the deputies are verified. If this violation of the Charter were to occur, we will return to this subject.</p></div>
    <div>
     <head>ELECTORAL NEWS.</head>
     <p>We believe it is necessary to inform about the election to the new legislature of deputies who have always taken a particular interest in colonial issues.</p>
     <p><persName ref="#AD">Mr. DELABORDE</persName> was elected both in <placeName>Paris</placeName> and <placeName>Étampes (Seine-et<pb n="30" facs="v1n1p30"/>Oise)</placeName>. Undoubtedly, one might wish for a bit more severity from this honorable deputy toward the advisors to the crown. Nevertheless, we will never hesitate to acknowledge Mr. Delaborde's pure intentions, and we are confident that the cause of people of color will always find support and protection in him.</p>
     <p><persName ref="#TRA">Mr. DE TRACY</persName> was elected in two electoral districts in Allier. This choice honors the constituents even more than the representative. Mr. de Tracy is the advocate of all noble causes and, in that capacity, the most genuine and eloquent voice for the oppressed in our colonies.</p>
       <p><persName ref="#FI">Mr. ISAMBERT</persName> was reelected in <placeName>Vendée Luçon</placeName>. We congratulate the voters of Luçon for renewing the mandate of the courageous defender of the deportees from <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, a man as upright as he is enlightened, who never lets an injustice pass without denouncing it and who has never failed the sacred cause of humanity.</p>
       <p><persName ref="#GdL">Mr. GAETAN DE LA ROCHEFOUCAULD</persName> was elected in the department of Cher. We can only applaud this choice, which sends one of the most zealous champions of the abolition of slavery back to the chamber.</p>
       <p>Among the most regrettable losses for people of color in the recent elections, we must first mention <persName ref="#ES">Mr. Eusèbe Salverte</persName>.</p>
       <p>In the <placeName>5th electoral district of Paris</placeName>, <persName ref="#THI">Mr. Thiers </persName> defeated this honorable citizen. It is the victory of intrigue over patriotic austerity personified in the person of Mr. Salverte. Mr. the Minister of the Interior is the pale reflection of <persName ref="#Talle">Mr. de Talleyrand</persName>, that archetype and patriarch of political roués, just as Mr. Salverte offers us the pure and living image of the virtuous <persName ref="#CAR">Carnot</persName>.</p>
       <p>Messrs. <persName ref="#Chara">Charamaule</persName> and <persName ref="#Meril">Mérilhou</persName> were also not re-elected. Let us hope that the re-elections that will take place due to double nominations will rectify this loss or, rather, this injustice.</p><pb n="31" facs="v1n1p31"/></div>
       <div>
       <head>MISCELLANEOUS NEWS.</head>
       <q><p>The following article, published by the <bibl type="periodical"><title ref="#MU">Moniteur</title></bibl> of <date>July 2</date>, is undoubtedly an indirect response to the new information provided about the state of the colony of <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>.</p>
       <p>In a letter dated May 21st, <persName ref="#EH">Vice-Admiral Halgan, Governor of Martinique</persName>, reported to the Minister of the Navy on a tour he had just made to several communes of the colony.</p>
       <p>The following passages are noteworthy in this report: </p>
        <floatingText><q><p>I am happy to report that the population is perfectly calm in all the areas I visited, and everyone is focused on taking advantage of a favorable year for the harvest.</p>
        <p>I conducted a thorough examination of the internal management of the plantations and the treatment the slaves receive from their masters. The administration generally seemed to me paternal and wise. Punishments are falling into disuse, and on most of the properties where I stopped, I observed that the masters had affection for their slaves who, without concern for the future, are content with the present, attached to their homes, the small comfort they enjoy, and willingly engage in work that does not exceed their physical capabilities.</p></q></floatingText>
           <p>Thus, Vice-Admiral Halgan's testimony regarding the situation of the slaves in Martinique is very similar to that of <persName ref="#JHD">Rear-Admiral Dupotet</persName>, whom he replaced, and who himself had merely confirmed the reports of his predecessor on this matter. This unanimity of opinions from individuals holding high positions and who were well-placed to know the truth seems to us of a nature to dispel many unjust prejudices and convince that the lot of the slaves in French colonies today leaves little to be desired for friends of humanity.</p>
           <p>Would it not be permissible to point out that this unanimity among the governors might only prove one thing, namely, that they have been, since their arrival,<pb n="32" facs="v1n1p32"/>influenced by the same factors? And as for Mr. Halgan in particular, who has barely arrived on the island, who has seen but a few plantations, and who dismisses the pleas presented to him, he is an authority that can, at this point, be challenged.</p></q>
           <p>(<emph>Messager</emph>.)</p>
           <p>If one is to believe the official newspaper, wouldn't the slaves be in a real <emph>el dorado</emph>, enjoying the tranquil and pure happiness that is only found in the shepherds' tales of Durfé and Florian? One must truly lack shame to advance such obviously false claims. Let the <title><emph>Moniteur</emph></title> then provide us with <persName>Admiral Halgan</persName>, report without reservations, and let it tell us whether the masters mentioned by the admiral as having murdered slaves are cherished by those who have witnessed the mutilation of their brothers. We call for the <emph>complete and unaltered report</emph>, but they dare not present it in its entirety, for it would suffice to reveal the extent of the slaves' happiness. In an upcoming issue, we will examine this report and address the <title><emph>Moniteur</emph></title>'s deliberate omissions.</p></div>
           <div xml:id="coloniesfr">
           <head>FRENCH COLONIES.</head>
           <head><placeName ref="#Cay">CAYENNE.</placeName></head>
           
           <p>We receive the following letter from <placeName ref="#Cay">Cayenne</placeName>, containing considerations on the electoral law, the importance of which our readers will understand.</p>
           <p><q>The colonial legislation published in <placeName ref="#GF">Guiana</placeName>,</q> it says, <q>is the subject of numerous complaints. Men of color have found truel disappointment in the electoral law; hence, those who could meet the 200 francs census have shown great indifference in participating in the elections. In contrast, whites have viewed the consecration of their privileges with a deep sense of satisfaction. Since the bill for the abolition of slavery has passed in England, our aristocrats would be willing to introduce two men of color into the colonial council out of sixteen, provided they are obedient individuals with no connection to <persName ref="#CB">Bissette</persName>, that eternal enemy of colonial interests.</q></p><pb n="33" facs="v1n1p33"/>
           <p><emph>SUPPLEMENT</emph></p>
           <q><p>Finally, they have reached this result, and two men of color have been admitted in the council, which is nothing but a true mockery, as one knows what influence they can have in deliberations. This de facto exclusion of men of color is a consequence of the exaggerated elevation of the electoral census, which has been designed in such a way as to keep them away.</p>
           <p>To be convinced of this, one need only look at the list of voters, established on October 13, 1833, for <placeName>French Guiana</placeName>.</p>
<table>
    <row>
      <cell role="label">Electors</cell>
      <cell role="label">Whites</cell>
      <cell role="label">Men of color</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>1st district City de Cayenne</cell>
      <cell>85</cell>
      <cell>66</cell>
      <cell>19</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>2nd - Cayenne Island, Canal and Tour de-l'lle.</cell>
      <cell>57</cell>
      <cell>55</cell>
      <cell>2</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>3rd - Districts  Tonnégrande and Mont-Sinéry.</cell>
      <cell>21</cell>
      <cell>12</cell>
      <cell>9</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>4th - Districts  de Rouza and la Comté.</cell>
      <cell>20</cell>
      <cell>18</cell>
      <cell>2</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>5th - Macouria, Kouron Synamary, Iracoula.</cell>
      <cell>38</cell>
      <cell>33</cell>
      <cell>5</cell>
    </row>
    <row>
      <cell>6th - Kair, Approuague, Oyapock.</cell>
      <cell>24</cell>
      <cell>19</cell>
      <cell>5</cell>
    </row>
</table>
</q>
</div>
<div>
<head><placeName ref="#MQ">MARTINIQUE.</placeName></head>

<p>The magistrates who are to compose the assize court in the Grand'Anse case are: <persName ref="#PER">Mr. Perrinelle</persName>, <persName ref="#RL">RICHARD-LUCY</persName> and <persName ref="#LePell">Mr. Le Pelletier-Duclary</persName>. Certainly, to transform innocent individuals into guilty ones, one could not have chosen better than these eternal judges under all regimes.</p>
 <p>Mr. Perrinelle, in the infamous 1824 trial, was one of the three judges out of twelve who voted for the death penalty. RICHARD LUCY, the prosecutor-general at that time, carried out the judgment that sentenced them to perpetual hard labor and branding, in disregard of the appeal to cassation by the condemned. Mr. Le Pelletier-Duclary, a troubled mind, presided, requesting the application of the penalty dictated by his colleague RICHARD-LUCY.</p>
 <p>If one still needs further proof of the morality of this case, suffice it to name the two colonial counselors, Messrs. <persName ref="#JorLa">MM. Jorna Lacalle</persName> and <persName ref="#ABour">Alphonse Bourke</persName>, who rendered the order<pb n="34" facs="v1n1p34"/>for the trial before the assizes. Mr. Jorna Lacalle voted for the death penalty in the 1824 case. This magistrate is utterly incompetent. Mr. Alphonse Bourke never completed his law degree, but in the 1824 trial, he voted for the penalty of perpetual hard labor, and as a conscientious judge, he personally ensured the execution of the judgment to which he had contributed. His victims, bound to the stake, could easily see him from one of the windows of the house of his godmother, Mme Duclésemur, where he was stationed.</p>
 <p>-On May 19th, the drawing of lots was carried out for the four assessors who will sit on the assize court. They are: Messrs. <persName ref="#Baud">Baudin</persName>, <persName ref="#HuyD">Huygues-Despointes</persName>, <persName ref="#DuDu">Duval-Dugué</persName> (of Grand'Anse) and <persName ref="#Germa">Germa</persName>. Mr. Duval-Dagué is a complainant and a key witness in the case he is called to judge. The indictment states, on page 39, that two of the accused looted rum on his plantation. The accused were unable to have him recused because Messrs. <persName ref="#AuA"><orig>Aubert-Armard</orig><corr>Aubert-Armand</corr></persName>, the public prosecutor, and <persName>Selles</persName>, the royal judge, did not find any incompatibility in a white man judging blacks and mulattos while being a complainant and a witness.<emph>The respective character of Assessor Duval-Dugué and the accused precludes any idea of recrimination between them...</emph></p>
 <p>-When the accused from Grand'Anse were transferred from the prison to the courthouse for the drawing of lots for the assessors, an extraordinary deployment of troops took place; sentinels placed every ten paces prevented any gathering. Leading were Messrs. <persName ref="#LTelem">Léonce</persName> and <persName ref="#ATelem">Arthur Télémaque</persName>, handcuffed like all their co-accused. An escort of eighty gendarmes was formed, and two companies of riflemen brought up the rear.</p>
 <p>-<persName><orig>M. Armand Aubert</orig><corr>M. Aubert-Armand</corr></persName>, the public prosecutor in Saint-Pierre, no doubt wanting to show his bias towards men of color, pursues them with a series of petty and miserable harassments, certain signs of a narrow and petty mind. This magistrate pushes the limits of propriety to the point of refusing the titles of <emph>Mr.</emph> and <emph>Mrs.</emph> to the relatives of the defendants in the Grand'Anse case who requested from him permission to see the unfortunate prisoners. It seems that the colonial atmosphere has a powerful effect on Europeans predisposed to vanity, as they quickly adopt such ridiculous and silly attitudes.</p><pb n="35" facs="v1n1p35"/>
  <p>Shortly after the July Revolution, this same magistrate, appointed royal judge in <placeName ref="#Cay">Cayenne</placeName>, did not hesitate to seek advice from one of the representatives of people of color in <placeName ref="#Par">Paris</placeName>. He wanted, he said, to enlighten himself in order to enforce the laws despite the ill will of the colonists. At that time, it is true, he often met this representative in the salons of the Minister of Justice, where he was received. This explains many things.</p>
</div>

<div>
<head><placeName ref="#GP">GUADELOUPE.</placeName></head>

<p>The political situation remains the same; however, there is more tranquility, which probably results less from the satisfaction of the parties than from the weariness they feel from these continuous and fruitless clashes. There has been, therefore, a sort of truce during which young white and colored people have come closer, shaken hands, and mutually promised to live as brothers from now on. May this commitment endure!</p>
 <p>The colonial council has not formulated a single decree; it has, until now, only engaged in opposition to the proposed improvements. Thus, the government, foreseeing that it will be overwhelmed sooner or later by this new institution, is not very pleased with it.</p>
 <p>The consolidation of the National Guard remains a question; the council has not yet made any decisions on this matter.</p></div>

 <div>
 <head><placeName ref="#BrB">BOURBON.</placeName></head>
 <p>The situation in this colony is beginning to feel the effects of some improvements made to the colonial system since the July Revolution. Caste prejudices are decreasing and will eventually disappear as institutions receive further development.</p>
 <p>There is hope that in the upcoming elections, people of color will be appointed to the general council. Already, a large number of votes are assured in favor of <persName ref="#LEl">Mr. Louis Elie</persName>, who enjoys great respect in the country.</p>
 <p>There is some activity in the organization of militias, and, in general, there is no reason to complain about local authorities. As for trade, it is virtually non-existent, and prospects for the future are quite bleak. <pb n="36" facs="v1n1p36"/>
 The re-election of <persName ref="#SUB">Mr. Sully-Brunet</persName>, as a delegate, which seemed doubtful, now appears to be assured.</p></div>

 <div>
 <head><placeName ref="#Alg">ALGER.</placeName></head>
 
 <p>This important possession, whose colonization we hope not to be delayed much longer, is beginning to enjoy some advantages - the inevitable results of its geographical position and the fertile land that extends from the sea to the foothills of the Atlas Mountains. The cessation of hostilities by the indigenous people, renewed confidence, and more active commercial transactions are the first outcomes of a fairer administration; indeed, justice is the primary good for any people, even the barbarians themselves sacrifice at its altars. So what benefits will France gain from this beautiful colony if the government manages it with the broad and philanthropic principles that alone can foster unity between the conquered and the conqueror!</p>
 <p><persName ref="#BEO">Ben-Omar</persName>, the former bey of <placeName>Titeri</placeName>, remains our faithful ally, and more powerful than armies, his conciliatory and wise words make us new allies or strengthen the peaceful disposition of those we have acquired.</p>
 <p><persName ref="#BZ">Ben-Zegri</persName>, a defector from Constantine, and the Jew Narboni, schemers who played a significant role during previous administrations, are now entirely disgraced and have lost the positions they managed to retain under all regimes. Upon hearing this news, the Atlas Mountains Arabs have shown willingness to draw closer to us, which they did not do previously.</p>
  <p>So, France should hasten to organize this beautiful colony, and above all, not forget this great principle: the art of governing is not the art of oppression.</p></div>

  <div xml:id="coloniesetr">
  <head>FOREIGN COLONIES.</head>
  <head><placeName ref="#StT">SAINT-THOMAS.</placeName></head>
  
  <p>If the colonial aristocracy contented itself with persecuting the men of color they deem dangerous, they would only partly fulfill their mission; they must also pursue, even in foreign lands, the unfortunate individuals who have incurred their animosity. Aristocratic <pb n="37" facs="v1n1p37"/>hatreds are as tenacious as those of kings, and just as <persName ref="#NIC">Nicnolas</persName> pursues the remnants of Poland worldwide, or <persName ref="#C-A">Charles-Albert</persName> claims his victims everywhere, colonial aristocracy also roars with fury when an unfortunate soul condemned to the executioner manages to escape it. Their minions track down such individuals everywhere, and if treaties, which they can render as flexible as laws, provide a means, extradition satisfies their thirst for mulatto blood and their obsession with punishment.</p>
  <p>After the events of the Grand'Anse, a man of color, <persName ref="#AHav">Mr. Auguste Havre</persName>, took refuge on the Danish island of <placeName ref="#StT">Saint-Thomas</placeName>, espérant y trouver un asile où ses persécuteurs ne viendraient pas le troubler. Son erreur était grande ! <persName>Mr. Morin</persName>, the son of a pharmacist from <placeName ref="#StP">Saint-Pierre</placeName>, went to Saint Thomas, recognized him, and this young colonist reported him as a supporter of the Grand'Anse revolution to <persName ref="#MACK">Admiral Mackau</persName>, Admiral Mackau, the commander of the Antilles station, who happened to be in that Danish colony at the time. This admiral who, for good reasons, shares colonial prejudices, requested the extradition of Mr. Auguste Havre in order to hand him over to the authorities in Martinique. He may well obtain it from the Danish government which, despite its usual gentleness, may be influenced by the fear of displeasing the French Ministry of the Navy.</p>
   <p>However, one must hope that the Saint Thomas government will be dignified enough not to sacrifice the peace and lives of the unfortunate individuals who come to its shores to the demands of a faction. Where would we be if the sacred laws of hospitality could be violated with impunity?</p></div>

   <div>
   <head><placeName ref="#STL">SAINTE-LUCIA.</placeName></head>

   <p>Before his departure from <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, former Governor <persName ref="#JHD">Dupotet</persName> solicited the extradition of several of the accused in the Grand'Anse conspiracy who had taken refuge on the island of <placeName ref="#STL">Sainte-Lucie</placeName> offering to exchange these unfortunate individuals for several escaped slaves from Saint Lucia. The English governor responded with dignity, stating that he did not accept the proposition and that he could not do so without the consent of his government. He believed too highly in the British ministry to entertain the notion that they would support such a dishonest action. Shortly <pb n="38" facs="v1n1p38"/>after, when this governor had passed away, Mr. Dupotet did not hesitate to repeat his request with his successor. Such measures can only be conceived by minds accustomed to sycophantic servility, which, likening humans to properties, believe that governments can trade, sell, or barter them at their whim. However, nothing here should be surprising; it is known that Admiral Dupotet, like all the minor colonial despots in charge of exploiting the colonies, is united in heart, affection, and interest with the privileged class in these regions.</p></div>

    <div>
    <head><placeName ref="#DOM">DOMINIQUE.</placeName></head>
    
    <p><placeName ref="#DOM">Dominica</placeName>, formerly a French colony but now part of <placeName ref="#GB">Great Britain</placeName> is, of all the Caribbean islands, the one where color prejudices have the least hold. One could even say that they no longer exist since people of color hold public office just like whites, without any rivalry between them except that of merit. It's not surprising, therefore, that this hospitable island, which is also adjacent to <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, Martinique, is a refuge for our unfortunate compatriots who are persecuted. Well, General <persName ref="#JHD">Dupotet</persName>, former governor of Martinique, has also made an offer to the governor of this colony for a deal in human flesh. Like his counterpart in <placeName ref="#STL">Saint-Lucia</placeName>, the latter has categorically refused. Honorable people can be found everywhere.</p></div>

    <div xml:id="necrologie">
    <head>NECROLOGY.</head>
    <head><persName ref="#LaF">THE GENERAL LAFAYETTE</persName></head>
    
    <p>Among the defenders of humanity, the most steadfast, unquestionably the most virtuous, and the most dedicated was <persName ref="#LaF">Lafayette</persName>Lafayette. He is no more! He passed away on May 20th from an illness he contracted while attending the funeral procession of the unfortunate Dulong. Despite experiencing some signs of illness himself, the old general insisted on being present and followed him devoutly, on foot, from the mortuary house to the grave prepared to receive the mortal remains of <pb n="39" facs="v1n1p39"/>our dear friend. The death of Dulong hastened Lafayette's own demise. For those of us who loved the young deputy and had the privilege of closely observing the admirable old age of the illustrious friend of <persName ref="#WAS">Washington</persName>, this was a double source of sorrow.</p>
    <p>The name of Lafayette will live as long as the selflessness of personal interests and pure, unwavering devotion to the cause of all are honored among men. Born into one of the oldest families in France and recently married to Madame de Noailles, a sudden transformation occurred in the excellent nature of this young French nobleman that permanently converted him to the democratic cause. It was like a revelation from above that determined the course of his life. He was but seeking a field where he could worthily employ his noble faculties when news of the American insurrection arrived in Europe. The young husband of Madame de Noailles, the dashing cavalier whose grace and elegant manners were praised at Versailles, had hardly read the American Declaration of Independence before he was won over. Reading the Bill of Rights turned Mr. de Lafayette into what we have seen him become: an indefatigable advocate for the oppressed, without regard to nationality or color, and the most sincere and ardent proponent of universal freedom.</p>
    <p>The intrepid volunteer arrived with incredible joy on the soil where he was about to shed his blood, where <persName ref="#JEF">Jefferson</persName>, <persName ref="#ADA"><orig>Adam</orig><corr>Adams</corr></persName> and <persName ref="#WAS">Washington</persName> awaited him, and he only returned after ensuring, along with his illustrious friends, through the surrender at Yorktown that ended the War of Independence in October 1781, the national existence of the great and serene republic that was always the object of his strong and patriotic affection.</p>
    <p>The political life of Mr. Lafayette is well-known: the generous role he played in the 1789 revolution, the strength of his logic, the simple clarity, and the unwavering faith with which he advocated, in the <orgName ref="#AN">National Assembly</orgName> and the <orgName ref="#AC">Constituent Assembly</orgName>, the sacred principles for which we fight, do not need to be reiterated. More than once, he raised his voice against the enslavement of black people and the injustice that excluded people of color from the exercise of their civic rights, but unfortunately, often without success.</p>
    <p>In this regard, he did not limit himself to theory; he also added practice, a rarer thing: starting in 1791, the General emancipated all the <pb n="40" facs="v1n1p40"/>slaves in his possessions in <placeName ref="#GF">French Guiana</placeName>. And on this account, he should be particularly dear to black people and people of color, for whom he never ceased to demand freedom and all the privileges of white citizens.</p>
     <p>In that same year, <date>1791</date>, he spoke these memorable words from the podium: <q>According to the decrees of the National Assembly, I believe it is clear that free <emph>men</emph>, property owners, cultivators, and taxpayers are <emph>citizens</emph>. Now, men of color are property owners, cultivators, taxpayers; are they <emph>men</emph>? </q>(Barely restrained applause. He continued with the subtle irony that was familiar to him): <q>For my part, I believe they are; and it is to express my opinion that I have requested the floor.</q>At this point, the audience could no longer contain themselves, and applause and cheers drowned out the speaker's voice.</p>
       <p>In the committee that was tasked, after the July Revolution, with examining a bill on the same issue, and which only produced the imperfect law that governs us, he displayed the greatest zeal for the extension of political rights for men of color. However, the stubbornness and narrow prejudices of his colleagues paralyzed his goodwill.</p>
       <p>Throughout his long career, concerning general politics, Mr. Lafayette made mistakes on occasion; in particular, he allowed himself to be deceived. We regret that he let slip, for the good of mankind, the few beautiful opportunities that presented themselves to him to settle everything according to his principles in the affairs of France and consequently in those of the entire world. But, despite all, it must be acknowledged that no man has, with a more noble character, followed a more honorable and upright course of conduct, even in the face of some apparent contradictions. Perhaps Lafayette alone, among historical figures, has managed to give practical and positive reality to what is meant by the sacred word <q>virtue</q>.</p>
          <p>HERHAN PRINT SHOP, 380, RUE SAINT-DENIS.</p>
          </div>
        </body>
        <back>
            <xi:include href="RdCv1n1-notes.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="entities.xml"/>
        </back>
    </text>
</TEI>
