<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../odd/tei_revue.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xml:id="RdCv1n1-en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Revue des Colonies V.1 N°1 (selection in English translation)</title>
                <editor>Maria Beliaeva Solomon</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <xi:include href="shared/editionStmt.xml"/>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Information about the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <front>
          <pb n="1" facs="v1n1p1"/>
            <titlePage>
                <titlePart type="main"><seg>REVUE</seg><lb/>DES<lb/><seg>COLONIES,</seg></titlePart>
                <titlePart type="sub">MONTHLY COMPENDIUM<ptr target="#n13FA"/><lb/> OF
                    POLITICS, ADMINISTRATION, JUSTICE, INSTRUCTION AND COLONIAL CUSTOMS,</titlePart>
                <byline>BY A <orgName ref="#SHC">SOCIETY OF MEN OF COLOR</orgName></byline>
                <byline>DIRECTED BY <persName ref="#CB">C.-A. BISSETTE</persName>.<lb/></byline>
                <docEdition>N°1<lb/>July.</docEdition>
                <docImprint><pubPlace><settlement>PARIS</settlement>,<lb/> AT THE OFFICE OF THE REVUE DES COLONIES,<lb/>46, RUE NEUVE-SAINT-EUSTACHE</pubPlace> <lb/> <date>1834</date>.</docImprint>
            </titlePage>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div>
               <pb n="3" facs="v1n1p3"/>
                <head><seg>REVUE</seg><lb/>DES <lb/><seg>COLONIES</seg></head>
                <div xml:id="prospectus">
                    <head rend="bold">Prospectus.</head>
                    <p> As of now, the colonies, generally speaking, only know of the great
                        principles of philanthropy in theory; of freedom in action, nothing at all. </p>
                    <p> The suffering and oppressed classes appeal and fight relentlessly, always in
                        vain. To stimulate the feeble good will to which our rulers limit
                        themselves, it is necessary to compile the just complaints that arise from
                        all sides. These claims, these grievances, to be successful, must receive
                        the greatest publicity: this is the object of our <bibl type="periodical"
                                ><title ref="#RdC">Revue</title></bibl>
                    </p>
                    <p> The debate floor <emph>today</emph> is no longer enough; petitions are
                        adjourned by the calculated negligence of rapporteurs or pushed back by the 
                        insolent agendas of the day. On the other hand, colonial authorities, always
                        disposed in favor of the privileged, cleverly evade the ministers' prescriptions. Against this hitherto successful tactic
                        of the partisans of aristocracy and privilege, it is necessary to finally
                        engage the power of public opinion, enlightened by a discussion always wise,
                        always true, but energetic and never timid, of the causes, whatever they may
                        be, which hinder the desirable fusion of the diverse populations of the
                            colonies.<ptr target="#n4F2A"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> For this purpose, a specialized journal is founded under the title of <bibl
                            type="periodical"><title ref="#RdC"> Revue des Colonies</title></bibl>,
                        with <persName ref="#CB">M. Bissette</persName> as director. </p>
                    <pb n="4" facs="v1n1p4"/>
                    <p> This journal is not only dedicated to all that concerns the colonies,
                        considered as a source of news and interesting facts apt to occupy the
                        leisure of the reader, but it devotes itself entirely to the political,
                        intellectual, moral and industrial interests of colonists of either
                            color.<ptr target="#n6CEA"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> Nothing that concerns the French colonies in particular will be omitted from
                        this monthly publication. The government, the administration, and the justice
                        system will be examined here with respect to both their actions and their
                        persons; for it is the latter that too often determines the spirit and
                        the manner in which populations are either oppressed or well looked
                        after.</p>
                    <p> The civil, political, and social rights of the two free classes, which,
                        having been hitherto divided, ought to be united, will here be advanced and
                        supported with indefatigable zeal. </p>
                    <p> The great question of the abolition of slavery, the cornerstone of liberty,
                        will here be treated with the most conscientious care and the most ardent
                        love of equality and of the general good.<ptr target="#n79DB"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>Arbitrariness and partiality will here be brought to face the court of public
                        opinion with no distinction between persons. The weak will find here support
                        and protection, the oppressor, punishment, the official, warranted blame for
                        his illegal acts, but respect for his person. </p>
                    <p> The <title>Revue des Colonies</title> will also concern itself with all the
                        changes made or projected in the legislation that governs foreign colonies
                        and inevitably affects our own in a powerful way.<ptr target="#n5699"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> National interests, in relation to the possession of
                            <placeName ref="#Alg">Algiers</placeName>, will find in the <title>Revue des
                            Colonies</title> a devoted and independent outlet.<ptr target="#n6ED7"/>
                    </p>
                    <p> Numerous and knowledgeable correspondents ensure that readers find as much
                        variety as edification in the articles of the <title>Revue des
                            Colonies.</title>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <pb/>
                <div xml:id="declaration">
                  <pb n="5" facs="v1n1p5"/>
                    <head>DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES.</head>
                    <p> The <title>Revue des Colonies</title> believes it must, above all, indicate
                        by what principles it will offer judgment upon men and things.<ptr
                            target="#n3E34"/> In its estimation, '89, in the immortal Declaration
                        of Rights voted by the <orgName ref="#AN">National Assembly</orgName>, laid
                        the future foundations of all truly democratic institutions; this is why we
                        inscribe this <title>Declaration</title> at the beginning of this
                        compendium: these are the tables of our law. </p>
                    <epigraph>
                        <cit>
                            <quote>The rights of men had been misunderstood, insulted for centuries;
                                they have been restored for all mankind by this
                                    <title>Declaration</title>, which will forever remain a rallying
                                cry against oppressors, and a law for legislators themselves. </quote>
                            <bibl type="legal">(Address of the <orgName>National Assembly</orgName>
                                to the French People, 11 February 1790.)</bibl>
                        </cit>
                    </epigraph>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head rend="bold">Excerpt</head>
                    <head>FROM THE MINUTES OF THE <orgName>NATIONAL ASSEMBLY</orgName> OF AUGUST 20,
                        21, 22, 23, 24, 26 AND OCTOBER 1st, 1789.</head>
                    <floatingText>
                        <body>
                            <div>
                                <head>DECLARATION OF THE RIGHTS OF MAN IN SOCIETY.<ptr
                                        target="#n7767"/></head>
                                <p>The representatives of the French People, formed into a National
                                    Assembly, considering ignorance, forgetfulness or contempt of
                                    the rights of man to be the only causes of public misfortunes
                                    and the corruption of Governments, have resolved to set forth,
                                    in a solemn Declaration, the natural, unalienable and sacred
                                    rights of man, to the end that this Declaration, constantly
                                    present to all members of the body politic, may remind them
                                    unceasingly of their rights and their duties; to the end that
                                    the acts of the legislative power and those of the executive
                                    power, since they may be continually compared with the aim of
                                    every political institution, may thereby be the more respected;
                                    to the end that the demands of the citizens, founded henceforth
                                    on simple and incontestable principles, may always be directed
                                    toward the maintenance of the Constitution and the happiness of
                                    all. </p>
                                <pb n="6" facs="v1n1p6"/>
                                <p> In consequence whereof, the National Assembly recognizes and
                                    declares, in the presence and under the auspices of the Supreme
                                    Being, the following Rights of Man and of the Citizen. </p>
                                <p xml:id="art1">Article 1.-Men are born and remain free and equal in rights.
                                    Social distinctions may be based only on considerations of the
                                    common good.</p>
                                <p>2.- The aim of every political association is the preservation of
                                    the natural and imprescriptible rights of man. These rights are
                                    Liberty, Property, Safety and Resistance to Oppression.</p>
                                <p xml:id="art3">3.-The source of all sovereignty lies essentially in the Nation.
                                    No corporate body, no individual may exercise any authority that
                                    does not expressly emanate from it.</p>
                                <p>4.- Liberty consists in being able to do anything that does not
                                    harm others: thus, the exercise of the natural rights of every
                                    man has no bounds other than those that ensure to the other
                                    members of society the enjoyment of these same rights. These
                                    bounds may be determined only by Law.</p>
                                <p><gap reason="accidental" unit="number" extent="1"
                                        /><supplied>5.-</supplied> The Law has the right to forbid
                                    only those actions that are injurious to society. Nothing that
                                    is not forbidden by Law may be hindered, and no one may be
                                    compelled to do what the Law does not ordain.</p>
                                <p><choice>
                                        <sic>5.-</sic>
                                        <corr>6.-</corr>
                                    </choice>The Law is the expression of the general will. All
                                    citizens have the right to take part, personally or through
                                    their representatives, in its making. It must be the same for
                                    all, whether it protects or punishes. All citizens, being equal
                                    in its eyes, shall be equally eligible to all high offices,
                                    public positions and employments, according to their ability,
                                    and without other distinction than that of their virtues and
                                    talents.</p>
                                <p>7.- No man may be accused, arrested or detained except in the
                                    cases determined by the Law, and following the procedure that it
                                    has prescribed. Those who solicit, expedite, carry out, or cause
                                    to be carried out arbitrary orders must be punished; but any
                                    citizen summoned or apprehended by virtue of the Law, must give
                                    instant obedience; resistance makes him guilty.</p>
                                <p> 8.- The Law must prescribe only the punishments that are
                                    strictly and evidently necessary; and no one may be punished
                                    except by virtue of a Law drawn up and promulgated before the
                                    offense is committed, and legally applied.</p>
                                <p>9.- As every man is presumed innocent until he has <pb n="7" facs="v1n1p7"/>
                                    been declared guilty, if it should be considered necessary to
                                    arrest him, any undue harshness that is not required to secure
                                    his person must be severely curbed by Law.</p>
                                <p>10. - No one may be disturbed on account of his opinions, even
                                    religious ones, as long as the manifestation of such opinions
                                    does not interfere with the established Law and Order.</p>
                                <p>11.- The free communication of ideas and of opinions is one of
                                    the most precious rights of man. Any citizen may therefore
                                    speak, write and publish freely, except what is tantamount to
                                    the abuse of this liberty in the cases determined by Law.</p>
                                <p>12.- To guarantee the Rights of Man and of the Citizen a public
                                    force is necessary; this force is therefore established for the
                                    benefit of all, and not for the particular use of those to whom
                                    it is entrusted.</p>
                                <p>13. For the maintenance of the public force, and for
                                    administrative expenses, a general tax is indispensable; it must
                                    be equally distributed among all citizens, in proportion to
                                    their ability to pay.</p>
                                <p>14. All citizens have the right to ascertain, by themselves, or
                                    through their representatives, the need for a public tax, to
                                    consent to it freely, to watch over its use, and to determine
                                    its proportion, basis, collection and duration.</p>
                                <p>15. Society has the right to ask a public official for an
                                    accounting of his administration.</p>
                                <p>16. Any society in which no provision is made for guaranteeing
                                    rights or for the separation of powers, has no Constitution.</p>
                                <p xml:id="art17">17.- Since the right to Property is inviolable and sacred, no one
                                    may be deprived thereof, unless public necessity, legally
                                    ascertained, obviously requires it, and just and prior indemnity
                                    has been paid.</p>
                                <closer> Excerpt from the minutes of the <orgName>National
                                        Assembly</orgName>, October 1, 1789. <lb/>Collated true to
                                    the original. <signed>Signed MOUNIER, president; Viscount DE
                                        MIRABEAU, DEMEUNIER, BUREAU DE Pusy, Bishop DE NANCY,
                                        FAYDEL, Abbot of EYMAR, secretaries. </signed>
                                </closer>
                            </div>
                        </body>
                    </floatingText>
                    <pb n="8" facs="v1n1p8"/>
                    <p>All of the principles of '89 are in this declaration; and, whatever one does,
                        there is in these principles, which the French revolution, by its republican
                        and imperial armies, has sown acrossed the land of <placeName>Europe</placeName>, and by its books everywhere in the universe, a
                        power which cannot be suppressed. </p>
                    <p>Certainly, if a man should be reminded of anything, it is his rights, which
                        aristocracies may well succeed in making obsolete here and there, but to
                        which the future belongs.</p>
                    <p>We ask that we compare the present state of our legislation with this page of
                        justice and liberty, that we examine whether the laws that are made for us
                        are in conformity with the principles of this declaration, which must be
                        forever, according to the fine expression of the <orgName>National
                            Assembly</orgName>, <emph>the law of the legislators
                        themselves</emph>. And if this examination clearly shows that the government,
                        whatever it may be, is not founded on this one equitable basis — the
                        enforcement of the rights of all — those who, like us and with the
                            <orgName>National Assembly</orgName>, will be convinced that
                            <emph>ignorance, forgetfulness or contempt for the rights of man are the
                            only causes of public misfortunes and the corruption of
                            governments</emph>, will triumphantly conclude that all the evil of the
                        present situation, in the colonies as everywhere, is absolutely a result of
                        this ignorance, of this forgetfulness or of this contempt, we cannot
                        precisely say which, as much on the part of the rulers as on that of the
                        governed.</p>
                    <closer>
                        <emph>The director</emph>, <signed><persName ref="#CB"
                            >BISSETTE</persName>.</signed>
                    </closer>
                </div>
                <div xml:id="regime">
                    <head>A LOOK AT THE COLONIAL REGIME AND ITS EFFECTS.</head>
                    <p>The deplorable events of Grand'Anse, <ptr target="#n590A"/>
                        <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName> have echoed through every
                        newspaper. Some, inspired by the authorities, in whose eyes all that is
                        emancipation becomes an object of terror, have presented this affair in an
                        unfavorable light to those who have limited themselves to passive
                            resistance.<ptr target="#n684A"/> Others, more benevolent, and above
                        all, more impartial, were careful not to pass premature judgment on a matter
                        of this nature: they knew that passion exaggerates both evil and good, and
                        that one should not <pb n="9" facs="v1n1p9"/>rush to adopt the words of a powerful and
                        often unjust party. </p>
                    <p>We too will attend to this matter, but by prefacing it with all the
                        considerations necessary to draw the correct conclusions.</p>
                    <p>These facts, which seem to us hardly believable, are repeated every day with
                        impunity in our colonies. And how could it not be so, when the men charged
                        with maintaining the laws are those most interested in violating them!
                        Arbitrariness is therefore only the sad corollary of a state of affairs
                        whose origins date back to a time of conquest, plunder and brutal violence.
                        We know that this arbitrariness exists; philosophy has decried it; power
                        itself seems to reject a shameful solidarity, and yet nothing real has been
                        done to put an end to it. Everything has been deceit and lies, from the
                        illusory measures against the slave trade, to the laws which seem to grant
                        men of color the rights of citizens, and a justice which one could not
                        truthfully represent scales in the hand.</p>
                    <p>These causes, which, deriving from the overall regime of the colonies, would seem foreign to the events of Grand'Anse, to which we will attend more particularly, 
                    <ptr target="#n65C6"/> are nevertheless attached to them by a multitude of threads:
                        for nothing in the fate of peoples, as in that of men, is isolated, and the
                        actual effects are often produced by causes lost to the depths of time.</p>
                    <p>The colonies too, despite their distance from the motherland, felt the
                        effects of the great political commotion which regenerated <placeName>France</placeName>. A long subjugation, largely exploited by
                        the aristocracy, had not been able to paralyze hearts so much that they did
                        not feel warmed by the rays of the sun of freedom. Men of color especially,
                        more advantaged than the unfortunate slaves, turned their eyes towards
                        France with love and confidence; they felt that each link which fell from
                        the chains of old Europe was for them a pledge of emancipation. The
                        emblazoned nobility, elevated to the rank of people, offered an edifying
                        lesson to the nobility of the skin,<ptr target="#n2BFD"/> which did not
                        even possess the prestige of the former's personal accomplishments. The
                        destruction of one was the sure guarantee of the destruction of the other.
                        Was not the emancipation of the people, who had long suffered the bondage <pb n="10" facs="v1n1p10"/>of the field, also a sign of freedom for the slaves? There was
                        therefore in the colonies what is still there today, an absurd aristocracy
                        clinging to its privileges and willing to go to any length to preserve them,
                        and on the other hand a population full of verve, of energy, beginning to
                        understand its rights and its dignity. </p>
                    <p>Such, then, was the position of the colonies when the July revolution,<ptr
                            target="#n9F29"/> so rich in prospects, made conceivable for a moment
                        the awakening of France. The new government, carried along, no doubt in
                        spite of itself, by the force of circumstance, not daring to lift the veil
                        which hid its ulterior motives, finally bowing before public opinion which
                        had just had its impact felt, erased the word <emph>regulations</emph> from
                        the article of the charter concerning the colonies. It declared that the
                        colonies would be governed by special <emph>laws</emph><ptr target="#n3257"
                        />. This tacit recognition of abuses of all kinds, originating in the
                        corrupted system of ordinences, stoked the hopes of those who could still
                        put some faith in ministers' promises. It was because they did not believe
                        that a government born of democracy could so quickly forget its origin; they
                        did not comprehend that the preservation of titles of nobility, of a
                        so-called upper chamber, and above all of an exaggerated civil list were
                        milestones laid down by the nascent power to constitute itself on bases
                        similar to that which the popular arm had just crushed. Did not the
                        preservation of the titled nobility in the motherland,<ptr target="#n917D"/> and the addition that was made to it of a Turcarets aristrocracy,<ptr
                            target="#n9C9A"/> clearly impart to the colonies that, except for a few
                        slight adjustments, their aristocracy of skin would be preserved along with
                        most of its privileges.</p>
                    <p>Indeed these fine particular <emph>laws</emph> were rendered so illusory as
                        to match the ordinances' arbitrariness,<ptr target="#n332A"/> differing from
                        them only by the hypocrisy of the name. For example, is not the electoral
                        law, establishing the political rights of whites and of men of color, a work
                        of perfidious deception? On the <placeName ref="#BrB">isle of
                            Bourbon</placeName> and of <placeName ref="#Cay">Cayenne</placeName>,
                        where the whites are in overwhelming majority, the electoral qualification
                        and eligibility are fixed at a lower rate, for there is no fear of
                        competition; but in the colonies of <placeName ref="#GP">Guadeloupe
                        </placeName> and <placeName ref="#MQ">Martinique</placeName>, where the
                        population of color, quite numerous, is of <pb n="11" facs="v1n1p11"/>average wealth, the
                        tax is preemptively raised to an unattainable level. Is there anything more
                        perfidious, I would even say more odiously ironic, than to thus concede the
                        right while prohibiting the means. Would it not have been truer to declare
                        outright that only whites could vote?<ptr target="#n0490"/></p>
                    <p>It became difficult, in the presence of this law of political organization,
                        creating or rather sanctioning a privilege, to allow for the action of the
                        popular will. The national guard, that
                        admirable institution of the métropole,<ptr target="#n5F16"/> had a pale
                        imitation in the colonies, where both the name and the democratic element of
                        election were carefully banished.</p>
                    <p>If France has a national guard, the colonies have a militia whose officers,
                        appointed by the governor, are generally taken from the white population and
                        from among a few men of color. These, to keep a rank obtained by favor,
                        devote themselves unquestioningly to the governor and become his
                        accomplices. We hasten to say that, among those promoted, we count friends
                        who have not wavered in their political opinions, but not all of them are
                        so. When power makes itself odious by its partiality, it always corrupts the
                        men who make themselves its supporters. What bonds can indeed unite men who
                        find themselves in a position so false as the colonial militia and its
                        leaders? Trust? It does not exist. Fraternity? it would be vain to search
                        for it there. So there remains only force, and it is indeed felt
                        everyday.</p>
                    <p>In the judicial system, abuses abound, and they are always to the advantage
                        of the aristocratic class. The royal courts and the magistrates' courts are
                        constituted in such a way as to let the whites become judges and parties in
                        their own cause. Finally, despite the very text of the charter, provost
                        courts can still bloody the soil of the colonies by legally assassinating
                        the innocent people they want to get rid of.</p>
                    <p>Well! in the presence of this boundless arbitrariness, leaning on their
                        numerous privileges, the whites groan and complain that the government has
                        dared to touch the holy ark of their power, by diminishing some of their
                        privileges. Political rights, they possess them all; the judicial power is
                        in their hands; law enforcement, they<pb n="12" facs="v1n1p12"/> direct and command it; but
                        it is not enough to suit their wounded pride. A principle, admittedly
                        without application, has been issued; the word equality was spoken, was it
                        not enough to offend those selfish and hard hearts for whom every
                        independent man who is not part of their league is but a worthless
                        rebellious slave?<ptr target="#n3701"/> Men of color, on the contrary,
                        confident in the government's feeble pledges of good will, waited patiently
                        for better days perfecting their political education so as to wield the
                        influence that they are entitled to in their country by their rights and
                        numbers. And what do they really want that is not wise and reasonable?
                        Placed in their land in the same position as the third estate in France
                        before the revolution, they then ask what this order commanded: liberty and
                        equality. But they are dealing with privileged people who are even more
                        tenacious than the nobility and clergy of France. These at least did not
                        have the impudence to deny the title of men to their adversaries.<ptr
                            target="#n8508"/>
                    </p>
                    <p>By what means, then, could the privileged recover the integrity of their
                        privileges? To ask the government for them was impossible, they would have
                        been told to bide their time; that the compromise was only a matter of
                        painful necessity; that, moreover, the liberties granted to the mulattoes
                        were purely illusory, being limited in reality to a few slight concessions
                        of sociability.<ptr target="#n6759"/> And furthermore these same concessions
                        often bend according to the whims of the aristocracy. These answers, which
                        would satisfy less impatient, and above all less prideful men, would have
                        deeply wounded those imperious masters whose despotism is exercised without
                        control over unfortunate slaves. It was therefore necessary to employ all
                        means, even calumny, to subjugate the class of color and crush it.<ptr
                            target="#n7A20"/> It had to be represented as factious, turbulent,
                        having sworn to destroy the whites and stopping at nothing, not murder, not
                        arson, to accomplish this. It is so easy to slander men who are not allowed
                        to defend themselves! To find guilty the enemy that one judges oneself! And
                        then the colonies also count among their ranks men who know how to create
                        conspiracies, foment them, cause them to arise at the right time, in order
                        to take advantage of them in their own interest. And what does it really
                        matter that the worthless blood of a few negroes comes to redden the ground!
                        What does it matter if a mulatto's head rolls on<pb n="13" facs="v1n1p13"/> the scaffold!
                        Mere trifles, when you consider the glorious result expected of it; that is,
                        the bondage of the many for the benefit of the few. Besides, the métropole
                        offers a few examples which would seem to authorize the colonies in this
                        Machiavellianism.</p>
                    <p>And so we have seen the birth of these imaginary plots, these conflagrations
                        whose frequency during certain periods bespeaks frightful mysteries.
                        Innocents have been accused, thrown into dungeons, tortured, shot without
                        pity when they allowed themselves a few complaints. Neither sex nor age
                        could soften these ferocious men who subject their slaves to the most
                        sophisticated cruelties, and their gold, thrown at the heads of the
                        proconsuls of the great nation, hides large stains of blood from their
                        eyes.</p>
                    <p>Ah! if some day an eloquent pen tearing the funereal veil which covers our
                        colonies, would retrace the history of domination of the possessors of
                        men; if it evoked from the depths of their tombs the sad victims who are
                        heaped there every day, never would a country defiled by tyranny offer such
                        horrible pages.<ptr target="#n4C92"/> All that we read of the Mésences, the
                        Caligulas, the Louis XIs,<ptr target="#n5DA0"/> all that our hearts refuse
                        to believe as too degrading for humanity, finds itself surpassed in the
                        nineteenth century by overseas Frenchmen. But these horrible scenes of
                        despotism have no place here, elsewhere we will reveal them by throwing the
                        names of their infamous authors among the ignominies of history. </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
        <back>
            <xi:include href="RdCv1n1-notes.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="entities.xml"/>
        </back>
    </text>
    
</TEI>
